<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<shell title="Interpretive and Advanced Skills">
   <scene id="1" type="1_Module_Intro">
      <video>USH_m4-1_s1</video>
      <credits>(tr)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (l)Gilbert Stuart/The Bridgeman Art Library/Getty Images, (r)Bettmann/Corbis, (bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock</credits>
   </scene>

   <scene id="2" type="2_Txt_Img_Animation">
      <video>USH_m4-1_s2</video>
      <credits>(tr)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (l)Library of Congress, Prints &amp; Photographs Division [LC-DIG-pga-03298], (r)Library of Congress, Prints &amp; Photographs Division [LC-DIG-cwpb-06941], (bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock</credits>
   </scene>

   <scene id="3" type="2_Txt_Img_Animation">
      <video>USH_m4-1_s3</video>
      <credits><![CDATA[<span style="font-size: 7px;">(tr)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (1)Stapleton Collection/Historical Picture Library/Corbis, (2)Library of Congress, Prints &amp; Photographs Division [LC-DIG-pga-03789], (3)North Wind/North Wind Picture Archives, (4)National Archives &amp; Records Administration, (5)National Archives &amp; Records Administration, (bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock</span>]]></credits>
   </scene>

   <scene id="4" type="2_Txt_Img_Animation">
      <video>USH_m4-1_s4</video>
      <credits>(tr)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (1)Kristy-Anne Glubish/Design Pics, (2)Chris Ryan/OJO Images/Getty Images, (bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock</credits>
   </scene>

   <scene id="5" type="2_Txt_Img_Animation">
      <video>USH_m4-1_s5</video>
      <credits>(tr)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock</credits>
   </scene>

   <scene id="6" type="2_Txt_Img_Animation">
      <video>USH_m4-1_s6</video>
      <credits>(tr)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock</credits>
   </scene>

   <scene id="7" type="3_txt_img_reading">
      <content>
         <header italic="false">The Growth of New England</header>
         <text><![CDATA[
		 	<p>The first enduring settlement in New England—the second in English America—resulted from the discontent of a congregation of Puritan Separatists in England. For years, Separatists had been periodically imprisoned and even executed for defying the government and the Church of England; some of them, as a result, began to contemplate leaving England permanently in search of freedom to worship as they wished—even though Puritans did not believe in religious freedom for all others.</p>
			<p>It was illegal to leave England without the consent of the king. In 1608, however, a congregation of Separatists from the hamlet of Scrooby began emigrating quietly, a few at a time, to Leyden, Holland, where they could worship without interference. [Later], some of the Separatists decided to move again, this time across the Atlantic, where they hoped to create the kind of community they wanted and where they could spread &quot;the gospel of the Kingdom of Christ in those remote parts of the world.&quot;</p>
			<p>Leaders of the Scrooby group obtained permission from the Virginia Company to settle in British America. From the king, [James I of England] they received formal assurances that he would &quot;not molest them, provided they carried themselves peaceably.&quot;  . . . Several English merchants agreed to advance the necessary funds in exchange for a share in the profits of the settlement at the end of seven years.</p>
			<p>. . . The migrating Puritans "knew they were pilgrims" even before they left Holland, their leader and historian William Bradford, later wrote. In September 1620 they left the port of Plymouth, on the English coast, in the Mayflower with thirty-five &quot;saints&quot; (Puritan Separatists) and sixty-seven &quot;strangers&quot; (people who were not full members of the church) aboard. By the time they sighted land in November, it was too late in the year to go on. Their original destination was probably the mouth of the Hudson River, in what is now New York. But they found themselves instead on Cape Cod. After exploring the region for a while, they chose a site for their settlement just north of the cape, an area Captain John Smith had named &quot;Plymouth&quot; (after the English port from which the Puritans had sailed) during an exploratory journey some years before. Plymouth lay outside the [Virginia] Company's territory, and the settlers realized they had no legal basis for settling there. As a result, forty-one male passengers signed a document, the Mayflower Compact, which established a civil government and proclaimed their allegiance to the king. Then, on December 21, 1820, the Pilgrims stepped ashore at Plymouth Rock.</p>
			<p>They settled on cleared land that had once been an Indian village until, three years earlier, a mysterious epidemic—known as &quot;the plague&quot; and probably brought to the region by earlier European explorers—had swept through the region and substantially depopulated it. The Pilgrims' first winter was a difficult one; half the colonists perished from malnutrition, disease and exposure. Still the colony survived.</p>
			<p>. . . In the end, the survival and growth of the colony depended crucially on the assistance they received from natives. Important Indian friends—Squanto and Samoset, among others—showed them how to gather seafood, cultivate corn, and hunt local animals.  . . . After the first harvest, in 1621, the settlers marked the alliance [with members of the Wampanoag] by inviting the Indians to join them in an October festival, the first Thanksgiving.</p>
			<p>But the good relationship between the settlers and the local Indians did not last. Thirteen years after the Pilgrims' arrival, a devastating smallpox epidemic—a result of further contact with English settlers—wiped out much of the Indian population around Plymouth.</p>
			<p>. . . The Pilgrims were always a poor community. As late as the 1640s, they had only one plow among them. But they clung to the belief that God had put them in the New World to live as a truly Christian community; and they were, on the whole, content to live their lives in what they considered godly ways.</p>
			<p>[The] Pilgrims were less committed to grand designs, less concerned about how they were viewed by others, than were the Puritans who settled the larger and more ambitious English colonies to their north.</p>
			<p style="font-size:90%;">From AMERICAN HISTORY: CONNECTING WITH THE PAST, 14th Edition, by Alan Brinkley, copyright &copy; 2012 The McGraw-Hill Companies, Inc.</p>
		 ]]></text>
      </content>
      <audio>USH_m4-1_s7</audio>
      <credits>(tr)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock</credits>
   </scene>

   <scene id="8" type="11_Activity_Drag_List">
      <matchingInstructions>Match the items on the left to the correct areas on the right.</matchingInstructions>
      <matching deductionFactor="2" maxAttempts="3" hasPoints="true" points="6" matchStyle="height:115px;" dropStyle="height:103px;">
         <matches title="">
            <match id="1">The Pilgrims had planned to settle near Cape Cod all along.</match>
			<match id="2"><![CDATA[
    <span style="font-size:90%">The Mayflower Compact established a new government in Plymouth that denied any connection to England or the king.</span>
]]></match>
			<match id="3">The Pilgrims left England, and later, Holland, for economic reasons.</match>
			<match id="4">The Plymouth colony would not have survived without the help of local Indians.</match>
			<match id="5"><![CDATA[Less than half the people aboard the <em>Mayflower</em> were Pilgrims.]]></match>
			<match id="6">The Plymouth colony remained smaller than neighboring colonies.</match>
         </matches>
         <drops title="True">5,4,6</drops>
		 <drops title="False">1,2,3</drops>
      </matching>
      <instructions>When you are done, check your results by clicking 'Check Answers'.</instructions>
      <audio>USH_m4-1_s8</audio>
      <credits>(tr)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock</credits>
   </scene>

   <scene id="9" type="3_txt_img_reading">
      <content>
         <header italic="false">The Puritan Experiment</header>
         <text><![CDATA[
		 	<p>Turbulent events in England in the 1620s (combined with the example of the Plymouth colony) created strong interest in colonization among other groups of Puritans. . . . By favoring Roman Catholicism and trying to destroy religious nonconformity, [English King] Charles I started the nation down the road that in the 1640s would lead to civil war. The Puritans were particular targets of Charles's policies. Some were imprisoned for their beliefs, and many began to consider the climate of England intolerable.</p>
			<p>. . . In the midst of this political and social turmoil, a group of Puritan merchants began organizing a new enterprise designed to take advantage of opportunities in America. At first their interest was largely an economic one. They obtained a grant of land in New England for most of the area now comprising Massachusetts and New Hampshire; they acquired a charter from Charles I (who was evidently unaware that they were Puritans) allowing them to create the Massachusetts Bay Company and to establish a colony in the New World; and they bought equipment and supplies from a defunct fishing and trading company that had attempted (and failed) to establish a profitable enterprise in North America earlier. In 1629, they were ready to dispatch a substantial group of settlers to North America.</p>
			<p>Among the members of the Massachusetts Bay Company, however, were a number of Puritans who saw the enterprise as something more than a business venture. They began to consider emigrating themselves and creating a haven for Puritans in New England. Members of this faction met secretly in Cambridge in the summer of 1629 and agreed to buy out the other investors and move en masse to America.</p>
			<p>As governor, the new owners of the company chose John Winthrop, an affluent, university-educated gentleman with a deep piety and a forceful character. Winthrop had been instrumental in organizing the migration, and he commanded the expedition that sailed for New England in 1630: seventeen ships and 1,000 people (who were, unlike the earlier migrants to Virginia, mostly family groups). It was the largest single migration of its kind in the seventeenth century. Winthrop carried with him the charter of the Massachusetts Bay Company, which meant that the colonists would be responsible to no company officials in England, only to themselves.</p>
			<p>The Massachusetts migration quickly produced several different new settlements. The port of Boston, at the mouth of the Charles River, became the company's headquarters and the colony's capital. But in the course of the next decade, colonists moved into a number of other new towns in eastern Massachusetts.</p>
			<p>Unlike the Separatist founders of Plymouth, the founders of Massachusetts had no intention of breaking from the Church of England. Yet, if they continued to feel any real attachment to the Anglican establishment, they gave little sign of it.</p>
			<p>The Massachusetts Puritans were not grim or joyless, as many observers would later portray them. They were, however, serious and pious people. They strove to lead useful, conscientious lives of thrift and hard work, and they honored material success as evidence of God's favor. . . . [Winthrop] and the other Massachusetts founders believed they were founding a holy commonwealth—a &quot;city upon a hill&quot;—that could serve as a model for the rest of the world.</p>
			<p>Like other new settlements, the Massachusetts Bay colony had early difficulties. During their first winter, an unusually severe one, nearly a third of the colonists died; others left in the spring. But more rapidly than Jamestown or Plymouth, the colony grew and prospered. The Pilgrims and neighboring Indians helped with food and advice. Affluent incoming settlers brought needed tools and other goods, which they exchanged for cattle, corn, and other produce of the established colonists and the natives. . . .The strong religious and political hierarchy ensured a measure of social stability.</p>
			<p>. . . Land and food shortages exacerbated the drastic Indian population decline that had begun as a result of epidemic diseases. There had been more than 100,000 Indians in New England at the beginning of the seventeenth century; by 1675, only 10,000 remained. This decline created despair among New England natives. It drove some Indians to alcoholism and others to conversion to Christianity. But it drove others to war.</p>
			<p>From AMERICAN HISTORY: CONNECTING WITH THE PAST, 14th Edition, by Alan Brinkley, copyright &copy; 2012 The McGraw-Hill Companies, Inc.</p>
		 ]]></text>
      </content>
      <audio>USH_m4-1_s9</audio>
      <credits>(tr)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock</credits>
   </scene>

    <scene id="10" type="11_Activity_Drag_List">
      <matchingInstructions>Match the items on the left to the correct areas on the right.</matchingInstructions>
      <matching deductionFactor="2" maxAttempts="3" hasPoints="true" points="6" matchStyle="height:100px;" dropStyle="height:88px;">
         <matches title="">
            <match id="1">The Puritans were targets of King Charles I due to their religious beliefs.</match>
			<match id="2">The Massachusetts Bay colony sought to break away from the Church of England.</match>
			<match id="3">At first, the group that secured the charter for the Massachusetts Bay colony was primarily interested in religious goals.</match>
			<match id="4">Unlike the Pilgrims in Plymouth, the Puritans did not suffer significantly during their first year in the New World.</match>
			<match id="5">The Puritan migration to Massachusetts Bay was larger than the Pilgrim migration to Plymouth.</match>
			<match id="6">Local American Indian groups helped the Puritans adapt to life in the colonies.</match>
         </matches>
         <drops title="True">1,5,6</drops>
		 <drops title="False">2,3,4</drops>
      </matching>
      <instructions>When you are done, check your results by clicking 'Check Answers'.</instructions>
      <audio>USH_m4-1_s10</audio>
      <credits>(tr)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock</credits>
   </scene>

   <scene id="11" type="2_Txt_Img_Animation">
      <video>USH_m4-1_s11</video>
      <credits>(tr)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock</credits>
   </scene>

   <scene id="12" type="11_Activity_Drag_List">
      <matchingInstructions>Match the items on the left to the correct areas on the right.</matchingInstructions>
      <matching type="dynamic" format="letter" deductionFactor="2" maxAttempts="3" hasPoints="true" points="6">
         <matches title="">
            <match id="1">A: Large-scale migration</match>
   			<match id="3">B: Sought to reform the world</match>
   			<match id="9">C: Separatists</match>
   			<match id="5">D: Eventually, poor relations with American Indians</match>
   			<match id="4">E: Freedom to worship God as they wished</match>
   			<match id="8">F: Small number of migrants</match>
   			<match id="7">G: Content with survival of the colony</match>
   			<match id="6">H: Puritans</match>
   			<match id="2">I: Were not responsible to a Company in England</match>
         </matches>
         <coord correct="1" x="303" y="102" />
         <coord correct="1" x="303" y="240" />
         <coord correct="1" x="333" y="170" />
         <coord correct="2" x="200" y="215" />
         <coord correct="2" x="200" y="125" />
         <coord correct="2" x="200" y="170" />
         <coord correct="3" x="75" y="170" />
         <coord correct="3" x="104" y="240" />
         <coord correct="3" x="104" y="102" />
         <drops title="">1,2,3</drops>
         <drops title="">4,5,6</drops>
         <drops title="">7,8,9</drops>
         <image>USH_m4-1_s12.jpg</image>
      </matching>
      <instructions>When you are done, check your results by clicking 'Check Answers'</instructions>
      <audio>USH_m4-1_s12</audio>
      <credits>(tr)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock</credits>
   </scene>

   <scene id="13" type="2_Txt_Img_Animation">
      <video>USH_m4-1_s13</video>
      <credits>(tr)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock</credits>
   </scene>

   <scene id="14" type="2_Txt_Img_Animation">
      <video>USH_m4-1_s14</video>
      <credits>(tr)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (c)Bettman/Corbis, (bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock</credits>
   </scene>

   <scene id="15" type="3_txt_img_reading">
      <content>
         <header italic="false">The Early Chesapeake</header>
         <text><![CDATA[
		 	<p>After James I issued his 1606 charters to the London and Plymouth Companies, the principal obstacle to founding new American colonies was, as usual, money.
. . . The London Company  . . . moved quickly and decisively. Only a few months after receiving its charter, it launched a colonizing expedition headed for Virginia—a party of 144 men aboard three ships: the <em>Godspeed</em>, the <em>Discovery</em>, and the <em>Susan Constant</em>.</p>
			<h1>The Founding of Jamestown</h1>
			<p>Only 104 men survived the journey. They reached the American coast in the spring of 1607, sailed into the Chesapeake Bay and up a river they named the James, and established their colony on a peninsula extending from the river's northern bank. They called it Jamestown. The colonists had chosen their site poorly. In an effort to avoid the mistake of Roanoke (whose residents were assumed to have been killed by Indians), they selected what they thought to be an easily defended location—an island setting that they believed would offer them security. But the site was low and swampy, hot and humid in the summer, and prey to outbreaks of malaria. It was surrounded by thick woods, which were difficult to clear for cultivation. And it lay within the territories of powerful local Indians, a confederation led by the imperial chief Powhatan. The result could hardly have been more disastrous.</p>
			<p>The initial colonists, too many of whom were adventurous gentlemen and too few of whom were willing laborers, ran into serious difficulties from the moment they landed. . . . [T]hese English settlers had had no prior exposure, and thus no immunity, to the infections of the new land. Malaria, in particular, debilitated the colony, killing some and weakening others so that they could do virtually no work.  Because the promoters in London demanded a quick return on their investment, the colonists spent much of their limited and dwindling energy on futile searches for gold. They made only slightly more successful efforts to pile up lumber, tar, pitch, and iron for export. Agriculture was a low priority, in part because they wrongly assumed that they could rely on the Indians to provide them with food.</p>
			<p>The London Company promoters had little interest in creating a family-centered community, and at first they sent no women to Jamestown. The absence of English women made it difficult for the settlers to establish any semblance of a &quot;society.&quot;</p>
			<p>. . . By January 1608, when ships appeared with additional men and supplies, all but 38 of the first 104 colonists were dead. Jamestown, now facing extinction, survived the crisis largely because of the efforts of twenty-seven-year-old Captain John Smith. He was already a famous world traveler, the hero of implausible travel narratives he had written and published. But he was also a capable organizer. Leadership in the colony had been divided among the several members of a council who quarreled continually. In the fall of 1608, however, Smith became council president and asserted his will. He imposed work and order on the community. He also organized raids on neighboring Indian villages to steal food. During the colony's second winter, fewer than a dozen (in a population of about 200) died. By the summer of 1609, when Smith was deposed from the council and returned to England, the colony was showing promise of survival.</p>
			<h1>Reorganization</h1>
			<p>The winter of 1609-1610 became known as the &quot;starving time,&quot; a period worse than anything they had suffered before. The local Indians, antagonized by John Smith's raids and other hostile actions by the early English settlers, killed off the livestock in the woods and kept the colonists barricaded within their palisade. [Later settlers] found only about 60 people (out of 500 residents the previous summer) still alive [by the following spring].</p>
			<h1>Tobacco</h1>
			<p>In 1612, the Jamestown planter John Rolfe began to experiment in Virginia with a harsh strain of tobacco that local Indians had been growing for years. He produced crops of high quality and found ready buyers in England. Tobacco cultivation quickly spread up and down the James. The character of this tobacco economy—its profitability, its uncertainty, its land and labor demands—transformed Chesapeake society in fundamental ways.</p>
			<p style="font-size:90%;">From AMERICAN HISTORY: CONNECTING WITH THE PAST, 14th Edition, by Alan Brinkley, copyright &copy; 2012 The McGraw-Hill Companies, Inc.</p>
		 ]]></text>
      </content>
      <audio>USH_m4-1_s15</audio>
      <credits>(tr)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock</credits>
   </scene>

   <scene id="16" type="2_Txt_Img_Animation">
      <video>USH_m4-1_s16</video>
      <credits>(bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock, (others)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images</credits>
   </scene>

   <scene id="17" type="11_Activity_Drag_List">
      <matchingInstructions>Match the items on the left to the correct areas on the right.</matchingInstructions>
      <matching type="dynamic" format="letter" deductionFactor="2" maxAttempts="3" hasPoints="true" points="6">
         <matches title="">
         <match id="1">A. Had a land grant from the Viriginia Company</match>
			<match id="2">B. Had a land grant from the London Company</match>
			<match id="3">C. Early settlers contained many family groups</match>
			<match id="4">D. Had big plans for their settlement</match>
			<match id="5">E. Had a land grant from the Massachusetts Bay Company</match>
			<match id="1">F. Celebrated the first Thanksgiving</match>
			<match id="5">G. Believed that their colony would serve as a model for the rest of the world</match>
			<match id="6">H. Owed money to investors</match>
			<match id="2">I. Organized raids on American Indian groups to steal food</match>
			<match id="7">J. Had difficulty adapting to their new environment</match>
         </matches>
		 <coord correct="1" x="83" y="200" />
         <coord correct="1" x="126" y="287" />
         <coord correct="2" x="161" y="74" />
         <coord correct="2" x="259" y="74" />
         <coord correct="3" x="208" y="245" />
         <coord correct="4" x="270" y="152" />
         <coord correct="5" x="333" y="200" />
         <coord correct="5" x="291" y="287" />
         <coord correct="6" x="144" y="152" />
         <coord correct="7" x="208" y="190" />
         <drops title="">1,2</drops>
         <drops title="">3,4</drops>
         <drops title="">5</drops>
         <drops title="">6</drops>
         <drops title="">7,8</drops>
         <drops title="">9</drops>
         <drops title="">10</drops>
         <image>USH_m4-1_s17.jpg</image>
      </matching>
      <instructions>When you are done, check your results by clicking 'Check Answers'</instructions>
      <audio>USH_m4-1_s17</audio>
      <credits>(tr)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock</credits>
   </scene>

   <scene id="18" type="Activity_Multiple_Choice">
      <instruction>Click on the correct answer.</instruction>
      <multiple_choice>
         <multiple>
            <question>A major difference between the early New England colonies and early Virginia was that</question>
            <answers>
               <answer>few colonists died in New England</answer>
			   <answer>American Indians in New England proved far more powerful than American Indians in Virginia</answer>
               <answer correct="true">most colonists came to Virginia seeking profit</answer>
			   <answer>religion played a more important role in Virginia</answer>
			   <answer>there were more women in Virginia than in New England</answer>
            </answers>
            <feedbackAudio>USH_m4-1_s18_FB</feedbackAudio>
         </multiple>
      </multiple_choice>
      <audio>USH_m4-1_s18</audio>
      <credits>(tr)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock</credits>
   </scene>

   <scene id="19" type="1_Module_Intro">
      <video>USH_m4-1_s19</video>
      <credits>(tr)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (l)Courtesy of the Massachusetts Historical Society., (cl)Pocahontas by Unknown/United States Senate, (b)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock</credits>
   </scene>

   <scene id="20" type="2_Txt_Img_Animation">
      <video>USH_m4-1_s20</video>
      <credits>(tr)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock</credits>
   </scene>

   <scene id="21" type="Activity_Multiple_Choice">
      <instruction>Click on the correct answer.</instruction>
      <multiple_choice>
         <multiple hasFigure="true">
            <question>Based on the table, which of the three colonial regions had the most industry (non-farm related activity)?</question>
            <answers>
               <answer correct="true">New England</answer>
			   <answer>Middle</answer>
			   <answer>Southern</answer>
            </answers>
            <figure verticalAlign="center">USH_m4-1_s21_view.jpg</figure>
            <feedbackAudio>USH_m4-1_s21_FB</feedbackAudio>
         </multiple>
      </multiple_choice>
      <audio>USH_m4-1_s21</audio>
      <credits>(tr)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock</credits>
   </scene>

   <scene id="22" type="Activity_Multiple_Choice">
      <instruction>Click on the correct answer.</instruction>
      <multiple_choice>
         <multiple hasFigure="true">
            <question>Based on the table, which of the three colonial regions relied MOST on agricultural production?</question>
            <answers>
               <answer>New England</answer>
			   <answer>Middle</answer>
               <answer correct="true">Southern</answer>
            </answers>
            <figure verticalAlign="center">USH_m4-1_s21_view.jpg</figure>
            <feedbackAudio>USH_m4-1_s22_FB</feedbackAudio>
         </multiple>
      </multiple_choice>
      <audio></audio>
      <credits>(tr)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock</credits>
   </scene>

   <scene id="23" type="Activity_Multiple_Choice">
      <instruction>Click on the correct answer.</instruction>
      <multiple_choice>
         <multiple hasFigure="true">
            <question>Based on the information in the table, which economic activity is common to all three regions?</question>
            <answers>
               <answer>tobacco</answer>
			   <answer>shipbuilding</answer>
			   <answer>iron</answer>
               <answer correct="true">livestock</answer>
			   <answer>naval stores</answer>
            </answers>
            <figure verticalAlign="center">USH_m4-1_s21_view.jpg</figure>
            <feedbackAudio>USH_m4-1_s23_FB</feedbackAudio>
         </multiple>
      </multiple_choice>
      <audio></audio>
      <credits>(tr)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock</credits>
   </scene>

   <scene id="24" type="Activity_Multiple_Choice">
      <instruction>Click on the correct answer.</instruction>
      <multiple_choice>
         <multiple hasFigure="true">
            <question>In which colony did the economy have the greatest impact on its overall success?</question>
            <answers>
               <answer correct="true">Jamestown</answer>
			   <answer>Massachusetts Bay</answer>
			   <answer>Plymouth</answer>
            </answers>
            <figure verticalAlign="center">USH_m4-1_s21_view.jpg</figure>
            <feedbackAudio>USH_m4-1_s24_FB</feedbackAudio>
         </multiple>
      </multiple_choice>
      <audio>USH_m4-1_s24</audio>
      <credits>(tr)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock</credits>
   </scene>

   <scene id="25" type="2_Txt_Img_Animation">
      <video>USH_m4-1_s25</video>
      <credits>(tr)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (l)Pocahontas by Unknown/United States Senate, (r)Hulton Archive/Getty Images, (bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock</credits>
   </scene>

   <scene id="26" type="2_Txt_Img_Animation">
      <video>USH_m4-1_s26</video>
      <credits>(tr)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (l)Pocahontas by Unknown/United States Senate, (r)Hulton Archive/Getty Images, (bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock</credits>
   </scene>

   <scene id="27" type="2_Txt_Img_Animation">
      <video>USH_m4-1_s27</video>
      <credits>(tr)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (l)Pocahontas by Unknown/United States Senate, (c)Image Asset Management Ltd./SuperStock, (r)The Gallery Collection/Corbis, (bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock</credits>
   </scene>

   <scene id="28" type="2_Txt_Img_Animation">
      <video>USH_m4-1_s28</video>
      <credits>(tr)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (l)Hulton Archive/Getty Images, (r)Christie's Images Ltd./SuperStock, (bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock</credits>
   </scene>

   <scene id="29" type="9_Activity_Image_Rollclick">
      <content>
         <header></header>
         <instruction></instruction>
      </content>
      <activity type="image">
         <image>USH_m4-1_s29.jpg</image>
         <hotspots>
			<hotspot dynamic="true" x="15" y="22"><![CDATA[
				<h1></h1>
				<p>Her given name was Matoaka but she was known to most by the nickname &quot;Pocahontas,&quot; which means &quot;little wanton,&quot; or a playful child.</p>
			]]></hotspot>
			<hotspot dynamic="true" x="15" y="125"><![CDATA[
				<h1></h1>
				<p>She was a favorite of John Smith, whether the &quot;saving his life&quot; scenario was real or just an American Indian ritual.</p>
			]]></hotspot>
			<hotspot dynamic="true" x="15" y="228"><![CDATA[
				<h1></h1>
				<p>John Smith described her as being full of wit and spirit.</p>
			]]></hotspot>
			<hotspot dynamic="true" x="15" y="331"><![CDATA[
				<h1></h1>
				<p>At age fifteen, she married an American Indian named Kocoum.</p>
			]]></hotspot>
			<hotspot dynamic="true" x="328" y="22"><![CDATA[
				<h1></h1>
				<p>During her marriage to Kocoum, Pocahontas was kidnapped by an Englishman from Jamestown. Her father, Powhatan, paid her ransom, which included the release of white captives.</p>
			]]></hotspot>
			<hotspot dynamic="true" x="328" y="125"><![CDATA[
				<h1></h1>
				<p>After her captivity, she moved to a European community near Jamestown called Henrico. Here, Pocahontas began her conversion to Christianity.</p>
			]]></hotspot>
			<hotspot dynamic="true" x="328" y="228"><![CDATA[
				<h1></h1>
				<p>Pocahontas met and fell in love with English tobacco farmer John Rolfe, who married her after her conversion to Christianity. Pocahontas was baptized and christened Rebecca.</p>
			]]></hotspot>
			<hotspot dynamic="true" x="328" y="331"><![CDATA[
				<h1></h1>
				<p>Pocahontas, Rolfe, and their son Thomas went to England in 1616 as part of a group hoping to gain financial support for the settlements in Virginia. Pocahontas was treated like a celebrity and met King James I and Queen Anne. Pocahontas fell ill as their voyage home began. She died of pneumonia or tuberculosis and was buried in England. She was 22 years old.</p>
			]]></hotspot>
         </hotspots>
      </activity>
      <audio>USH_m4-1_s29</audio>
      <credits>(tr)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (l)Hulton Archive/Getty Images, (r)Pocahontas by Unknown/United States Senate, (bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock</credits>
   </scene>

   <scene id="30" type="Activity_Multiple_Choice">
      <instruction>Click on the correct answer.</instruction>
      <multiple_choice>
         <multiple hasFigure="true">
            <question>Both images present realistic portraits of Pocahontas.</question>
            <answers>
               <answer>TRUE</answer>
               <answer correct="true">FALSE</answer>
            </answers>
            <figure verticalAlign="center">USH_m4-1_s30_view.jpg</figure>
            <feedbackAudio>USH_m4-1_s30_FB</feedbackAudio>
         </multiple>
      </multiple_choice>
      <audio>USH_m4-1_s30</audio>
      <credits>(tr)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (inset) (l)Hulton Archive/Getty Images, (r)Pocahontas by Unknown/United States Senate, (bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock</credits>
   </scene>

   <scene id="31" type="Activity_Multiple_Choice">
      <instruction>Click on the correct answer.</instruction>
      <multiple_choice>
         <multiple hasFigure="true">
            <question>Both portraits are influenced by the style of the period in which they were created.</question>
            <answers>
               <answer correct="true">TRUE</answer>
               <answer>FALSE</answer>
            </answers>
            <figure verticalAlign="center">USH_m4-1_s30_view.jpg</figure>
            <feedbackAudio>USH_m4-1_s31_FB</feedbackAudio>
         </multiple>
      </multiple_choice>
      <audio>USH_m4-1_s31</audio>
      <credits>(tr)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (inset-l)Hulton Archive/Getty Images, (r)Pocahontas by Unknown/United States Senate, (bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock</credits>
   </scene>

   <scene id="32" type="Activity_Multiple_Choice">
      <instruction>Click on the correct answer.</instruction>
      <multiple_choice>
         <multiple>
            <question>Which of the following statements MOST accurately represents both images of Pocahontas?</question>
            <answers>
               <answer>The images exaggerate her American Indian characteristics.</answer>
			   <answer>The images tend to be critical of American Indian culture.</answer>
               <answer correct="true">The images indicate she was a public figure.</answer>
			   <answer>The images ignore American Indian characteristics.</answer>
			   <answer>The images are meant to glorify European culture.</answer>
            </answers>
            <feedbackAudio>USH_m4-1_s32_FB</feedbackAudio>
         </multiple>
      </multiple_choice>
      <audio>USH_m4-1_s32</audio>
      <credits>(tr)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock</credits>
   </scene>

   <scene id="33" type="2_Txt_Img_Animation">
      <video>USH_m4-1_s33</video>
      <credits>(tr)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (c)Chris Ryan/OJO Images/Getty Images, (bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock</credits>
   </scene>

   <scene id="34" type="2_Txt_Img_Animation">
      <video>USH_m4-1_s34</video>
      <credits>(tr)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock</credits>
   </scene>

   <scene id="35" type="2_Txt_Img_Animation">
      <video>USH_m4-1_s35</video>
      <credits>(tr)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (1)Commercial Eye/Iconica/Getty Images, (2)Photodisc/Getty Images, (3)Stan Fellerman/Corbis, (4)Colorblind Images/Blend Images/Getty Images, (bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock</credits>
   </scene>

   <scene id="36" type="3_txt_img_reading">
      <content>
         <header italic="false">"Lee and Grant"</header>
         <text><![CDATA[
		 	<p>The son of a distinguished—though not wealthy—Virginia family, Robert E. Lee was raised in the socially exclusive world of the aristocratic South. From the beginning, he seemed marked by fate for brilliant success. At West Point, he excelled both in his studies and his social life, impressing teachers and fellow cadets with his talent and good nature. As an army officer in the war with Mexico, he performed with brilliance and courage.</p>
			<p>Offered command of the Union troops at the beginning of the Civil War, Lee refused, unable to oppose his fellow Virginians. He later commanded the army of Northern Virginia.</p>
			<p>A hero to Southerners during the war, Lee felt a responsibility to set an example of Southern honor in defeat. His swearing of renewed allegiance to the United States after the war inspired thousands of former Confederate soldiers to follow his example. As president of Washington College in Virginia (later renamed Washington and Lee), Lee encouraged his students to put the war behind them and to behave as responsible citizens.</p>
			<p>Lee died at the age of 63. In his last moments, he seemed to give orders to his troops, and then at last called out, &quot;Strike the tent!&quot;</p>
			<p>From THE AMERICAN VISION, 14th Edition, by Joyce Appleby, Alan Brinkley, Albert S. Broussard, James M. McPherson, and Donald A. Ritchie, copyright &copy; 2003 The McGraw-Hill Companies, Inc.</p>
		 ]]></text>
      </content>
      <audio>USH_m4-1_s36</audio>
      <credits>(tr)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock</credits>
   </scene>

   <scene id="37" type="3_txt_img_reading">
      <content>
         <header italic="false">"Lee and Grant"</header>
         <text><![CDATA[
		 	<p>Before his victories in Kentucky and Tennessee, Ulysses S. Grant had been a mediocre West Point cadet, a failed businessperson, and an undistinguished army officer. More than any other Union commander, however, Grant changed the strategy—and the outcome—of the Civil War. Grant's restless urge for offensive fighting and his insistence on &quot;unconditional surrender&quot; at Fort Donelson convinced Lincoln to place the general in command of all of the Union troops in 1864. Lincoln's confidence was not misplaced. Despite mounting casualties and accusations that he was a &quot;butcher,&quot; Grant pushed relentlessly until he finally accepted Lee's surrender at Appomattox, Virginia.</p>
			<p>The Union's enthusiasm for its victorious general made Grant a two-term president after the war, although scandals in his administration marred his reputation. The Civil War had been the high point of Grant's life, the challenge that brought out his best qualities. More than any monument or memorial—including Grant's Tomb, in New York City—Lincoln's defense of his embattled general during the war sums up Grant's character and achievement: &quot;I can't spare this man; he fights.&quot; </p>
			<p>From THE AMERICAN VISION, 14th Edition, by Joyce Appleby, Alan Brinkley, Albert S. Broussard, James M. McPherson, and Donald A. Ritchie, copyright &copy; 2003 The McGraw-Hill Companies, Inc.</p>
		 ]]></text>
      </content>
      <audio>USH_m4-1_s37</audio>
      <credits>(tr)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock</credits>
   </scene>

   <scene id="38" type="2_Txt_Img_Animation">
      <video>USH_m4-1_s38</video>
      <credits>(tr)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (1)Library of Congress, Prints &amp; Photographs Division [LC-DIG-pga-03298], (2)Library of Congress, Prints &amp; Photographs Division [LC-DIG-cwpb-06941], (3)Colorblind Images/Blend Images/Getty Images, (4)BananaStock/JupiterImages/Getty Images, (bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock</credits>
   </scene>

   <scene id="39" type="2_Txt_Img_Animation">
      <video>USH_m4-1_s39</video>
      <credits>(tr)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (l)Library of Congress, Prints &amp; Photographs Division [LC-DIG-pga-03298], (r)Library of Congress, Prints &amp; Photographs Division [LC-DIG-cwpb-06941], (bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock</credits>
   </scene>

   <scene id="40" type="2_Txt_Img_Animation">
      <video>USH_m4-1_s40</video>
      <credits>(tr)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock</credits>
   </scene>

   <scene id="41" type="End_Multiple_Choice">
      <instruction>Click on the correct answer.</instruction>
      <multiple_choice>
         <multiple>
            <question>A Venn diagram can only be used to compare and contrast information from two sources.</question>
            <answers>
               <answer>TRUE</answer>
               <answer correct="true">FALSE</answer>
            </answers>
            <feedbackAudio></feedbackAudio>
         </multiple>
		 <multiple>
            <question>All AP U.S. History Exam questions that require you to compare or contrast feature those specific clue words.</question>
            <answers>
               <answer>TRUE</answer>
               <answer correct="true">FALSE</answer>
            </answers>
            <feedbackAudio></feedbackAudio>
         </multiple>
		 <multiple>
            <question>You can compare and contrast information provided as text, or in images, tables, maps, or graphs.</question>
            <answers>
               <answer correct="true">TRUE</answer>
               <answer>FALSE</answer>
            </answers>
            <feedbackAudio></feedbackAudio>
         </multiple>
		 <multiple>
            <question>Writing a block-format essay is not incorrect, but it may cause you to lose some points on the AP U.S. History exam.</question>
            <answers>
               <answer correct="true">TRUE</answer>
               <answer>FALSE</answer>
            </answers>
            <feedbackAudio></feedbackAudio>
         </multiple>
		 <multiple hasTextFigure="true">
            <question>Which of the following illustrates a way in which the early American colonies were similar?</question>
            <answers>
               <answer>The British Empire in America was equal to the French- and Spanish-American empires.</answer>
               <answer correct="true">Trade centers emerged from each geographic section.</answer>
            </answers>
         <figure>
				<header></header>
				<text><![CDATA[
					<p>The English colonization of North America was part of a larger effort by several European nations to expand the reach of their increasingly commercial societies. Indeed, for many years, the British Empire in America was among the smallest and weakest of the imperial ventures there, overshadowed by the French to the north and the Spanish to the south.</p>
					<p>In the British colonies along the Atlantic seaboard, new agricultural and commercial societies gradually emerged—in the South, centered on cultivation of tobacco and cotton and reliant on slave labor; and in the northern colonies, centered on traditional food crops and based mostly on free labor. Substantial trading centers emerged in such cities as Boston, New York, Philadelphia, and Charleston, and a growing proportion of the population became prosperous and settled in these increasingly complex communities. By the early eighteenth century, English settlement had spread from northern New England (in what is now Maine) south into Georgia.</p>
					<p>From AMERICAN HISTORY: CONNECTING WITH THE PAST, 14th Edition, by Alan Brinkley, copyright &copy; 2012 The McGraw-Hill Companies, Inc.</p>
				 ]]></text>
			</figure>
            <feedbackAudio></feedbackAudio>
         </multiple>
		 <multiple hasTextFigure="true">
            <question>Which of the following illustrates a way in which the early American colonies differed?</question>
            <answers>
               <answer>relative growth</answer>
               <answer correct="true">source of labor</answer>
            </answers>
         <figure>
				<header></header>
				<text><![CDATA[
					<p>The English colonization of North America was part of a larger effort by several European nations to expand the reach of their increasingly commercial societies. Indeed, for many years, the British Empire in America was among the smallest and weakest of the imperial ventures there, overshadowed by the French to the north and the Spanish to the south.</p>
					<p>In the British colonies along the Atlantic seaboard, new agricultural and commercial societies gradually emerged—in the South, centered on cultivation of tobacco and cotton and reliant on slave labor; and in the northern colonies, centered on traditional food crops and based mostly on free labor. Substantial trading centers emerged in such cities as Boston, New York, Philadelphia, and Charleston, and a growing proportion of the population became prosperous and settled in these increasingly complex communities. By the early eighteenth century, English settlement had spread from northern New England (in what is now Maine) south into Georgia.</p>
					<p>From AMERICAN HISTORY: CONNECTING WITH THE PAST, 14th Edition, by Alan Brinkley, copyright &copy; 2012 The McGraw-Hill Companies, Inc.</p>
				 ]]></text>
			</figure>
            <feedbackAudio></feedbackAudio>
         </multiple>
		 <multiple hasFigure="true">
            <question>In what way are these two images similar?</question>
            <answers>
               <answer correct="true">They both portray national leaders in a way that is compatible with the nations themselves.</answer>
               <answer>They both seek to project the power and might of great empires.</answer>
            </answers>
         <figure verticalAlign="center">USH_m4-1_s41_viewA.jpg</figure>
            <feedbackAudio></feedbackAudio>
         </multiple>
		 <multiple hasFigure="true">
            <question>In what way do these two images differ?</question>
            <answers>
               <answer>Only George Washington is seen as a powerful figure.</answer>
               <answer correct="true">Only King George III wears the trappings of the monarchy.</answer>
            </answers>
         <figure verticalAlign="center">USH_m4-1_s41_viewA.jpg</figure>
            <feedbackAudio></feedbackAudio>
         </multiple>
		 <multiple hasFigure="true">
            <question>Based on the maps, which of the following statements is true?</question>
            <answers>
               <answer correct="true">Between the 1780s and 1812, settlers moved onto land near the Ohio, Mississippi, and Illinois rivers.</answer>
               <answer>By 1812, American Indians had ceded all land east of the Mississippi River to the United States.</answer>
            </answers>
         <figure verticalAlign="center">USH_m4-1_s41_viewB.jpg</figure>
            <feedbackAudio></feedbackAudio>
         </multiple>
		 <multiple hasFigure="true">
            <question>Based on the maps, which of the following statements is true?</question>
            <answers>
               <answer>Prophet's influence did not last into the 1800s.</answer>
               <answer correct="true">Both Tecumseh and Prophet were influential American Indian leaders.</answer>
            </answers>
         <figure verticalAlign="center">USH_m4-1_s41_viewB.jpg</figure>
            <feedbackAudio></feedbackAudio>
         </multiple>
      </multiple_choice>
      <audio>USH_m4-1_s41</audio>
      <credits>(tr)VisionsofAmerica/Joe Sohm/Digital Vision/Getty Images, (bkgd)Comstock/PunchStock</credits>
   </scene>
</shell>
