<TextReading>
	<slideInfo>
		<hText>Peasants and Lords: Mutual Obligations on the Medieval Manor</hText>
		<image>images/euro_s1-2_s17.jpg</image>
		<audio>audio/euro_s1-2_s17.mp3</audio>
		<mainText><![CDATA[<p>Manors developed from the agricultural estates of the old Roman Empire and the new division of land made by early medieval kings.  . . . Virtually all manors consisted of the lord’s home and outbuildings (barn, mill, etc) and at least one village in which the peasants resided and worked. <br /><br />. . . Medieval peasants lived close together in the village and traveled out to their fields. Fields were organized in strips, with each family using some and the lord owning a large number himself. The church, too, owned some strips for the priest’s support. <br /><br />The survival of the peasants depended not only on the crops they grew on their plowed strips, but also on their wise use of the other spaces. Serfs grazed their oxen and working horses, as well as their sheep and goats, on common pastureland. . . . Farm animals supplemented a grain diet as well, with milk and cheese (especially from goats) and some meat. Peasants ate very little meat because their animals were too valuable to be disposed of in this way. However, sometimes the lord gave the peasants his unwanted portions of meat (tails, hoofs, or entrails) to make soup. <br /><br />Medieval European peasants were at the bottom of the social order in that they had obligations to people “above” them, but no one below them owed them any commitments. Most medieval peasants were personally free (that is, they were not slaves), but they were bound to the land. When a lord received a land grant from the king, he also gained the service of the peasants who worked the land. Peasants who were semi-free in this way—that is, personally free yet not free to move from their village—were called serfs. <br /><br />Beyond their obligation to remain on the land, serfs owed their lords many other things—roughly divided into goods and labor. For example, they had to give the lord a percentage of their crops or whatever livestock they raised . . . They also owed him their labor. On some manors, serfs had to work as many as three days a week on the lord’s demesne lands, those set aside for his own consumption and use. . . . Serfs did not owe military service—fighting was the privilege of the nobility. <br /><br />. . . In exchange for peasant services, lords provided things that required a large investment of capital: mills, barns, ovens, large draft animals, and the like. However, the lords primarily offered justice and protection to the serfs. In times of war, for example, the presence of a well-armed warrior and his followers could make the difference between a village’s survival and its destruction. <br /><br />. . . All serfs did not enter voluntarily into this contract in which they exchanged their labor for safety. Sometimes armed lords who needed their lands cultivated forced peasants into servitude on their estates. Late in the Middle Ages . . . many serfs decided the benefits of protection were not worth the price.<br /><br /><font size='8'>Source: From THE WEST IN THE WORLD, 4th Edition, by Dennis Sherman and Joyce Salisbury, copyright © 2011 The McGraw-Hill Companies, Inc.</font></p>]]></mainText>
	</slideInfo>	
</TextReading>