<TextReading>
	<slideInfo>
		<hText><![CDATA[From <font face='t-Italic'>Women, the Family, and Freedom: The Debate in Documents</font>]]></hText>
		<image></image>
		<audio>audio/euro_m1-5_s21.mp3</audio>
		<mainText><![CDATA[<p>The questioning of women’s subordinate status in marriage was, of course, closely connected to the problem of female education. Indeed, the long-standing debate on the education of women likewise entered a new phase in the mid-eigthteenth century. In 1761, Jean-Jacques Rousseau (who had attracted a large female audience with his novel <font face='lc-Italic'>La Nouvelle Héloïse</font>) asserted that women, created to please men, should be educated exclusively to be good wives and mothers; such mothers, in turn, would raise daughters entirely absorbed in pleasing men. Rousseau’s youthful enthusiasm for natural, unrestricted self-realizing human development, for a social contract that would eliminate inequality, for a good yet simple life, has inspired the dreams—and nightmares—of successive generations of reformers. Paradoxically, these egalitarian dreams seemed to require the backing of an unchanging and stable nurturing force. Fundamental to Rousseau’s thought, therefore, lay the most conservative, the most time-honored assumptions about the social relations of the sexes. He reconsecrated for all women a role exclusively within the family on the grounds of biological determinism and gave new authority to deep-rooted attitudes concerning the “separate [male and female] spheres.” 
Though a few women writers initially applauded Rousseau’s overall assertions, a cluster of well-known female authors in France and England indignantly challenged his views on woman’s nature and role. The most eloquent among them were Catherine Macaulay and Mary Wollstonecraft in England, and Germaine de Staël in France. They protested against Rousseau’s argument from differing points of view, raising issues as diverse as the importance of emotional independence for wives, economic independence for single women and widows, and the nefarious influence we now call sex-role conditioning. Against Rousseau’s assertion that because all girls enjoyed playing at mothering dolls they were inherently competent “nurturers,” the authors pointed out that girls were conditioned for this role by a society that allowed them to play with nothing but dolls. Catherine Macaulay further proposed that boys—as well as girls—should be taught the “graces,” in order to blue the strong sexual dichotomy and dependence of weak women on strong men on which Rousseau insisted. Madame de Staël, a brilliant and creative writer, was personally outraged by Rousseau’s denigrating aspersions against married women authors, whose writing (he implied) would cause them to neglect their wifely duties. 
. . . With the republican revolutions of the later eighteenth century and early nineteenth centuries, Enlightenment social criticism provided ammunition for action against the established order. The question of women’s relationship to the new republican states immediately came to the fore. Although the issues that precipitated the 1789 Paris revolts were economic . . . the underlying discontent of the eighteenth century, both in Europe and in the American colonies, was expressed in political terms: men objected to autocratic and arbitrary government.  . . . Yet the women, watching, did not always remain silent.
<br/><font size='8'>Excerpts from WOMEN, THE FAMILY AND FREEDOM: THE DEBATE IN DOCUMENTS VOL 1750-1880, Susan Groag Bell, Karen M. Offen, Copyright © 1974 by the Board of Trustees of the Leland Stanford Jr. University. With the permission of Stanford University Press, www.sup.org.</font><p>]]></mainText>
	</slideInfo>	
</TextReading>