<TextReading>
	<slideInfo>
		<hText>High Middle Ages: Social Impact</hText>
		<image>images/euro_s1-2_s25.jpg</image>
		<audio>audio/euro_s1-2_s25.mp3</audio>
		<mainText><![CDATA[<p>With more food available, there was a significant decline in malnutrition.  In the peasantry, fewer infants died at birth and more people began to live longer lives.  At the same time, improved agricultural techniques required fewer people to work the land.  Many eleventh century peasants, who had acquired a bit of personal wealth, were able to buy themselves out of serfdom.<br /><br />Where did these people go?  They went to the medieval towns that were just being created.  Where were they being created?  In some cases at cross-roads where travelers and traders might want to spend a night.  Therefore, some peasants became inn-keepers and property owners.  Many towns emerged at a good site to cross a river.  Innsbruck, in Austria, is one such example. <font face='c-Italic' size='18'>Bruck</font>, meaning bridge in the Austrian dialect of German, became part of the town’s name where the bridge was built across the Inn River.  Cambridge, in England, is a similar example – a bridge across the River Cam. <br /><br />In the Holy Roman Empire (Germany), many town names include the word <font face='c-Italic' size='18'>Burg</font> (meaning protective fortress) as a suffix.  They typically built protective walls.  Hamburg, in north-central Europe, is a good example.  Many of these towns will grow to become cities.<br /><br />At their start, the towns were given charters by monarchs.  That meant that the inhabitants were freed from feudalism.  They were citizens with certain safeguards and no longer subjects of the feudal lord.  In Germany, a popular saying went: <font face='c-Italic' size='18'>Stadtluft macht frei”</font> (city air makes you free).<br /><br />The importance of this development cannot be overstated.  The first peasants to arrive in the towns were the first generation of a new social class in Western Civilization and it will produce more change than any other class.  It is often referred to as the middle class due to its status above the peasantry and its ranking below the two privileged classes (clergy and nobility).  More accurate names for this class would include terms such as bourgeoisie in French, <font face='c-Italic' size='18'>Buergertum</font> in Dutch and German, and gentry in English.<br /><br />Many members of this new class engaged in trade as merchants or bankers.  Town-centered commerce developed out of their activities.  The use of banknotes and minted coins represents a major economic advance beyond manorialism.<br /><br />Other members of the middle class worked as artisans or craftsmen.  Coopers, cobblers, tailors, and silversmiths began producing fine products that no one could have imagined (or have afforded) in the Early Middle Ages.  New family names were adopted by the trades that were being practiced.  Tailor, in England, or Schneider (literally meaning cloth-cutter) in central Europe, are good examples.  The quality of work in a given trade was closely observed and protected by stringent Guild Systems.</p>]]></mainText>
	</slideInfo>	
</TextReading>