<TextReading>
	<slideInfo>
		<hText>The Late Middle Ages: The Hundred Years’ War (1337-1453)</hText>
		<image>images/euro_s1-2_s33.jpg</image>
		<audio>audio/euro_s1-2_s33.mp3</audio>
		<mainText><![CDATA[<p>The Hundred Years’ War, which actually lasted longer than a hundred years, was fought entirely on French soil.  It began as a civil squabble between two groups of French nobles. One group favored recognizing a “King of France” while the other did not. The Burgundians, who did not want to be controlled by a French king, became a major factor in the war. The Church leaders in France also opposed a central leader. They worried that the power of the Church would be reduced by a powerful king.<br /><br />England gradually became involved in what was initially a French civil war.  The Norman kings of England, descended from the Norman French William “the Conqueror”, claimed France for themselves. The English entered the war on the side opposed to having a French king.  Many of the major early battles were English victories due to the skill of the English archers and their longbows.<br /><br />Towards the end of the war, however, the people of France became a factor. They wanted to rid France of the English. A teen-aged girl, Joan of Arc, played a mysterious role in rallying the French nobility to victory over the English at Orleans. With this victory, the rightful King of France ascended the throne. Captured by the English, handed over to the Burgundians, convicted of heresy by the Church, burned at the stake, and canonized (in 1920), Joan of Arc remains one of the most intriguing figures in French history.<br /><br />In the end, England is on the losing side.  An English civil war, the War of the Roses, will cause further setback for England.  It will take the driving efforts of King Henry VIII to initiate the recovery of the country.<br /><br />France is also a loser.  Since the war was fought entirely on its own soil, the country suffers an economic setback and a sharp population decline.  The French nobility is devastated.  The weak nobility allowed the kings of France to gradually establish absolute control over the government, at the nobility’s expense. This will continue through the reign of Louis XVI in the eighteenth century.</p>]]></mainText>
	</slideInfo>	
</TextReading>