<TextReading>
	<slideInfo>
		<hText>Letter from Marie Dentière to Queen Marguerite of Navarre, 1539</hText>
		<image></image>
		<audio>audio/euro_m4-1_s34.mp3</audio>
		<mainText><![CDATA[<p>Not only for you, my lady, did I wish to write this letter, but also to give courage to other women detained in captivity, so that they might not fear being expelled from their homelands, away from their relatives and friends, as I was, for the word of God. And principally for the poor little women, wanting to know and understand the truth, who do not know what path, what way to take, in order that from now on they be not internally tormented and afflicted, but rather that they be joyful, consoled, and led to follow the truth, which is the Gospel of Jesus Christ.<br/>For as you well know, the female sex is more shameful than the other, and not without cause. For until now, the scriptures have been hidden from them. No one dared say a word about it, and it seemed that women should neither read nor hear anything in the holy scriptures. That is the main reason, my lady, that has moved me to write to you, hoping in God that henceforth women will not be so scorned as in the past. For, from day to day, God changes the heart of his people for the good. That is what I pray will soon happen throughout the land.<br/>. . . Not only will certain slanderers and adversaries of truth try to accuse us of excessive audacity and temerity, but so will certain of the faithful, saying that it is too bold for women to write to one another about matters of scripture. We may answer them by saying that all those women who have written and have been named in holy scripture should not be considered too bold. Several women are named and praised in holy scripture, as much for their good conduct, actions, demeanor, and example as for their faith and teaching.<br/>. . . Even though in all women there has been some imperfection, men have not been exempt from it. Why is it necessary to criticize women so much seeing no woman never sold or betrayed Jesus, but a man named Judas? Who are they, I pray you, who have invented and contrived so many ceremonies, heresies, and false doctrines on earth if not men? And the poor women have been seduced by them. Never was a woman found to be a false prophet, but women have been misled by them.<br/>Therefore, if God has given grace to some good women, revealing to them by his holy scriptures something holy and good, should they hesitate to write, speak, and declare it to one another because of the defamers of truth? Ah, it would be too bold to try to stop them, and it would be too foolish for us to hide the talent that God has given us, God who will give us the grace to persevere to the end. Amen.
		
<br/><br/><font size='8'>From EPISTLE TO MARGUERITE DE NAVARRE AND PREFACE TO A SERMON BY JOHN CALVIN by Marie Dentière, translated by Mary B. McKinley. Copyright © 2004 The University of Chicago. Reprinted by permission of The University of Chicago Press.</font></p>]]></mainText>
	</slideInfo>	
</TextReading>