<TextReading>
	<slideInfo>
		<hText><![CDATA[John Calvin]]></hText>
		<image></image>
		<audio>audio/euro_m4-2_s23.mp3</audio>
		<mainText><![CDATA[<p>Outwardly, Calvinism seemed to have much in common with Lutheranism. Both emphasized people’s sinfulness, lack of free will, and helplessness; both rejected good works as a means of salvation; both accepted only two sacraments, baptism and communion; both regarded all occupations as equally worthy in the sight of God; both strongly upheld established political and social authority; [both allowed the clergy to marry], and both had similar views of faith, people’s weaknesses, and God’s omnipotence. But the emphases in Calvinism were very different.
In arguing for justification by faith alone, Luther assumed that God can predestine a person to be saved but rejected the idea that damnation can also be preordained. Calvin’s faith was much sterner. He recognized no such distinction: if people are damned, they should praise God’s justice, because their sins certainly merit such a judgment; if people are saved, they should praise God’s mercy, because their salvation is not a result of their own merits. Either way, the outcome is predestined, and nothing can be done to affect an individual’s fate. It is up to God to save a person; he then perseveres in his mercy despite the person’s sins; and finally, he alone decides whether to receive the sinner into the small band of saints, or elect, whom he brings into heaven. Calvin’s was a grim but powerful answer to the age-old Christian question: How can sinful human beings gain salvation?
Calvin believed that our behavior here on earth, whether good or bad, is no indication of our fate. He did suggest that someone who is to be saved by God is likely to be upright and moral, but such conduct is not necessarily a sign of salvation. However, because we should try to please God at all times, and because our communities ought to be fitting places for the elect to live, we must make every effort to lead lives worthy of one of the elect.
Calvin therefore developed a strict moral code for the true believer that banned frivolous activities, like dancing, in favor of constant self-examination, austerity, and sober study of the Bible. To help the faithful observe such regulation, he reestablished public confessions… and required daily preaching. He made services starkly simple: Stripped of ornaments, worship concentrated on uplifting sermons and the celebration of communion. He rejected Zwingli’s interpretation, saying instead that Christ’s body and blood were actually and not just symbolically present. But unlike Luther, he held that they were present only in spirit and were consumed only spiritually, by faith.
To supervise the morals of the faithful and ensure that the community was worthy of the elect, Calvin gave his church a strict hierarchical structure. It was controlled by church officials called deacons and by lay elders, who were able to function even in the hostile territories where many Calvinists found themselves. A body of lay elders called the consistory served as the chief ecclesiastical authority. These elders enforced discipline and had the power of excommunication, though local officials imposed the actual punishments—most notoriously in 1553, when a radical who denied the Trinity, Michael Servetus, was invited to Geneva and then executed for heresy.
Calvin’s system produced a cohesiveness and organization achieved by no other Protestant church. [Calvin’s book, <font face='lc-Italic'>The Institutes of the Christian Religion</font>] spelled out every point of faith and practice in detail—an enormous advantage for Calvin’s followers at a time when new religious doctrines were still fluid… Tight discipline controlled the entire system, with the result that Calvinists believed they were setting a moral and religious example that the entire world would eventually have to follow. They were part of a privileged community from whom the elect would be drawn. Thus, they could be oppressive when they had power, yet holy rebels when they were a minority. After all, since they were freed of responsibility for their own salvation, they were acting selflessly at all times. Like the children of Israel, they had a mission to live for God, and this sense of destiny was to be one of Calvinism’s greatest strengths.
<font size='8'>From THE WESTERN EXPERIENCE, 10th Edition, by Mortimer Chambers et al, copyright © 2010 The McGraw-Hill Companies, Inc.</font></p>]]></mainText>
	</slideInfo>	
</TextReading>