<TextReading>
	<slideInfo>
		<hText>The Black Death</hText>
		<image></image>
		<audio>audio/euro_m4-1_s18.mp3</audio>
		<mainText><![CDATA[<p>In the fourteenth century, a horrible pandemic swept in from the east and devastated Europe. The disease spread over vast areas, helped by increased trade from ships moving through the Mediterranean and by the expansion of the Mongol Empire…<br/>The [Bubonic plague] killed a shocking one-third to one-half of the population… Disease hit crowded cities hardest: Paris may have lost half its population and Florence as much as four-fifths…<br/>The psychological impact of so great a plague was perhaps even more important than the actual loss of life. Law and tradition broke down, and many survivors saw no point in trying to preserve medieval customs…<br/>As medicine failed to offer solace for this horrifying disease, many could only conclude that God’s wrath brought the devastation. Responding to this notion, some people resorted to extreme measures to try to bring God’s aid against the plague. One group—the flagellants—thought that by inflicting pain on themselves, they could ask God to relieve the suffering of others…<br/>In their fear, some people turned against their neighbors, and in many cities, Jews were accused of bringing the plague by poisoning wells. The persecution fell particularly heavily on Jewish communities in Germany… More than sixty major Jewish communities in Germany had been destroyed [and thousands of Jews killed] by 1351. Many Jews fled to eastern Europe—to Russia and Poland—where they received protection, and many Jewish communities moved their homes even farther east.<br/>As an immediate result of the plague, the European countryside suffered a disabling shortage of labor… Free laborers, detecting an opportunity, began to demand higher wages, prompting some countries to pass laws freezing earnings… This policy enraged peasants across Europe. Determined to resist, they roamed the countryside, burning manor houses and slaughtering the occupants… Eventually, all the revolts were suppressed, with many peasants and their leaders massacred. Yet the violence, the labor shortages, and the prevailing belief that things were changing had begun to erode the old medieval manorial system. Over time, peasants who owed only rent gradually replaced serfs who had owed labor as well as rent. The situation of peasants in western Europe improved more quickly than that of those in eastern Europe….<br/>Revolts [also] broke out in many towns throughout Europe… Improvements for urban workers would eventually come with the labor shortages caused by the high death rates. But the rural and urban revolts of the fourteenth century set off social conflicts that periodically resurfaced throughout Western history. <br/><br/><font size='8'>From THE WEST IN THE WORLD, 4th Edition, by Dennis Sherman and Joyce Salisbury, copyright © 2011 The McGraw-Hill Companies, Inc.</font></p>]]></mainText>
	</slideInfo>	
</TextReading>