<TextReading>
	<slideInfo>
		<hText>Grouping Documents of Similar Points of View</hText>
		<image></image>
		<audio>audio/euro_m3-1_s36.mp3</audio>
		<mainText><![CDATA[<font face='lc-Bold' size='18'>Document 1: “1914 V: The Soldier”, by Rupert Brooke</font><br/>If I should die, think only this of me:<br/>That there's some corner of a foreign field<br/>That is for ever England. There shall be<br/>In that rich earth a richer dust concealed;<br/>A dust whom England bore, shaped, made aware,<br/>Gave, once, her flowers to love, her ways to roam,<br/>A body of England's, breathing English air,<br/>Washed by the rivers, blest by suns of home.<br/>And think, this heart, all evil shed away,<br/>A pulse in the eternal mind, no less<br/>Gives somewhere back the thoughts by England given;<br/>Her sights and sounds; dreams happy as her day;<br/>And laughter, learnt of friends; and gentleness,<br/>In hearts at peace, under an English heaven.<br/><br/><font face='lc-Bold' size='18'>Document 2: “DULCE ET DECORUM EST”, by Wilfred Owen, 8 October 1917–March 1918</font><br/>Bent double, like old beggars under sacks, <br/>Knock-kneed, coughing like hags, we cursed through sludge, <br/>Till on the haunting flares we turned our backs <br/>And towards our distant rest began to trudge. <br/>Men marched asleep. Many had lost their boots <br/>But limped on, blood-shod. All went lame; all blind; <br/>Drunk with fatigue; deaf even to the hoots  <br/>Of tired, outstripped Five-Nines that dropped behind.<br/>Gas! Gas! Quick, boys! – An ecstasy of fumbling, <br/>Fitting the clumsy helmets just in time; <br/>But someone still was yelling out and stumbling, <br/>And flound'ring like a man in fire or lime . . . <br/>Dim, through the misty panes and thick green light, <br/>As under a green sea, I saw him drowning. <br/>In all my dreams, before my helpless sight, <br/>He plunges at me, guttering, choking, drowning. <br/>If in some smothering dreams you too could pace <br/>Behind the wagon that we flung him in, <br/>And watch the white eyes writhing in his face, <br/>His hanging face, like a devil's sick of sin; <br/>If you could hear, at every jolt, the blood <br/>Come gargling from the froth-corrupted lungs, <br/>Obscene as cancer, bitter as the cud  <br/>Of vile, incurable sores on innocent tongues, <br/>My friend, you would not tell with such high zest<br/>To children ardent for some desperate glory, <br/>The old Lie; Dulce et Decorum est <br/>Pro patria mori*.<br/>*(It is sweet and fitting to die for one's country.)<br/><br/><font face='lc-Bold' size='18'>Document 3: from <font face='t-Italic'>The Adventures of Telemachus</font>, 1699</font><br/>The evils of war never fail to drain a nation, and put it in danger of ruin, even while it is most victorious; with how great advantage soever they begin it, they are never sure to end it without being exposed to the most tragical chances of fortune. . . . And though you should hold victory chained in your camp, you destroy yourself in destroying your enemies. You dis-people your country, leave your ground uncultivated, interrupt commerce, nay, which is far worse, you weaken your laws and suffer manners to be corrupted. <br/><br/><font face='lc-Bold' size='18'>Document 4: from <font face='t-Italic'>The Present War No Burden to England</font>, 1692</font><br/>War is said to be a curse to a nation; ‘tis true, but ‘tis only so where the seat of war is, where all is committed to plunder, rapine, fire, flames, and utter destruction. But how many nations have raised their name, and rendered themselves famous and rich by war? And what have not advantageous wars brought into this nation? Our conquests . . . have for certain advanced our riches. 		
	]]></mainText>
	</slideInfo>	
</TextReading>

