<TextReading>
	<slideInfo>
		<hText><![CDATA[<p><font face='lc-Bold'>from "What is the Third Estate?" by Abbé Sieyes, January 1789</font></p>]]></hText>
		<image></image>
		<audio>audio/euro_m3-2_s23.mp3</audio>
		<mainText>
			<![CDATA[<p>It suffices here to have become obvious that the so-called use of a privileged order for public service is only a fantasy. With it, all that is laborious in this service is performed by the Third Estate. Without it, superior places would be infinitely better filled, that they would naturally be the lot and reward of talent and recognized services, and that if the privileged succeed in usurping all the lucrative and honorary posts, it is both a heinous inequity for the majority of citizens and a betrayal to the public.<br/><br/>Who then would dare say that the Third Estate does not have within it all that is necessary to form a complete nation? It is the strong and robust man whose arm is still chained. If the privileged order is removed, the nation would not be anything less but something more. So what is the Third Estate? Everything, but one that is shackled and oppressed. What would it be without the privileged order? Everything, but one that is free and thriving. Nothing can go forward without it; all would be infinitely better without the others.<br/><br/>It is not sufficient to have shown that the privileged, far from being useful to the nation, can only weaken and harm it. It is necessary to still prove that the noble order does not need to enter into the social organization, that it can well be a burden for the nation, but that it would not be able to form a homeland.<br/><br/>First, it is not possible in the number of all the fundamental parts of a nation to find or place the noble caste. I know individuals in too large a number that infirmity, incapacity, incurable idleness, or the torrent of bad habits are rendered strangers to the works of society. The exception and abuse are everywhere outside of the rule, and especially in a vast empire. But we agree that the less abuses there are, the better the state can be ordered. The worst order of all would be where those not particularly isolated but an entire class of citizens would take pride in resting immobile in the middle of general movement, and would consume the greater part of the product, without having contributed anything to reproduce it. One such class is assuredly foreign to the nation by its laziness.<br/><br/>The noble order is not less foreign to our environment, by its privileges – civil and political.<br/><br/>What is a nation? A body of associates living under a common law and represented by the same legislature, etc.<br/><br/>Is it not exceedingly clear that the noble order has some privileges, some exemptions, even rights, separated from rights of the majority of citizens? Thus it deviates from the common order, the common law. So civil rights already render it a people apart from the larger nation. It is truly an <font face='c-Italic'>imperium in imperio</font> (government within a government).<br/><br/>With regard to political rights, it also exercises them apart. It has its own representatives, who are not at all charged with the power of the people. The body of the deputies is seated apart, and when it is assembled in the same room, with the deputies of the simple citizens, it is not less authentic that the representation is essentially distinct and separate. It is foreign to the nation, first by its origin, since its mission does not come from the people, then by its purpose, since it consists in defending, not the general interest but the particular interest. The Third Estate embraces all that belongs to the nation, and all that is not part of the Third Estate cannot be considered as being a part of the nation.<br/><br/>What is the Third Estate? Everything.<br/><br/><font size='8'>French translation by Joyce Isler</font></p>]]>
		
		</mainText>
	</slideInfo>	
</TextReading>