<TextReading>
	<slideInfo>
		<hText><![CDATA[The Catholic Reformation]]></hText>
		<image></image>
		<audio>audio/euro_m4-2_s25.mp3</audio>
		<mainText><![CDATA[   The Catholic revival that started in the 1530s was partly a Counter-Reformation, a response to criticisms by Luther and others. But it was also a Catholic Reformation, a movement within the Church to reform itself. The papacy was aware of its loss of control over millions of Christians, but a great deal of the effort to put the Church’s house in order was a result of strong faith and a long-standing determination to purify belief and practice.
   The ecumenical, or general, council of Church leaders called by [Pope] Paul [III] finally assembled at Trent, a northern Italian city, in 1545, and met irregularly until the delegates managed to complete their work in 1563. 
   In keeping with Paul’s instructions, the Council of Trent gave more of its time to the basic issue of Church doctrine than to the problem of reform. Nearly all of its decisions were intended to establish clear definitions of practice and belief and to end long-standing theological uncertainties or differences of opinion… Catholicism from then on would be committed primarily to the outward, sacramental heritage of Christianity. In this view, the Bible is not the exclusive authority for the believer: Church tradition holds an equal place in establishing religious truth. Human will is free, good works as well as faith are a means of salvation, all seven sacraments are channels of grace, and Christ’s sacrifice is reenacted in every Mass. The Council of Trent endorsed the special position of the priest and insisted that God be worshipped with appropriately elaborate ceremonies and rites… [Priests were to remain celibate and were not allowed to marry.]
   The Latin translation of the Bible prepared chiefly by St. Jerome, was decreed to be a holy text, a decision which rebutted humanists and other scholars who had found mistranslations of Greek and Hebrew in Jerome’s work; and in direct contrast to the Protestants, gorgeous ritual was heavily stressed, which encouraged artists to beautify church buildings and ceremonies.
   The achievement of the council was to adjust the Church to the world. Many ordinary people, troubled by the stern self-denial and predestination taught by most Protestant churches and sects, preferred the traditional comfort, ceremony, and support Catholicism had long offered. They were ready to champion their old faith as soon as its leadership restored its sense of purpose by removing abuses and defining doctrines. And the new discipline of the Church was apparent in the council’s effort to deal with morality as thoroughly as with belief. When it gave its approval to the Inquisition and to the “Index of Forbidden Books,” which informed all Catholics of the heretical works they were not allowed to read, the council signaled the determination of the Church to recover the ground it had lost.
   <font size='8'>From THE WESTERN EXPERIENCE, 10th Edition, by Mortimer Chambers et al, copyright © 2010 The McGraw-Hill Companies, Inc.</font>]]></mainText>
	</slideInfo>	
</TextReading>