<TextReading>
	<slideInfo>
		<hText><![CDATA[The Powers of Parliament in England]]></hText>
		<image></image>
		<audio>audio/euro_m4-4_s18.mp3</audio>
		<mainText><![CDATA[                                                         <font face='c-Italic' size='20'>The House of Commons</font><br/><br/>Background: <font face='lc-Italic'>James’ views on monarchical powers were not accepted by members of Parliament. Indeed, from the beginning of his reign through the reign of his son Charles I, king and Parliament struggled over their relative powers. Along with other problems, this struggle culminated in the 1640s with the outbreak of civil war and the eventual beheading of Charles I. The nature of this struggle is partially revealed in the following statements issued by the House of Commons in 1604 to the new king, James I.</font>
Now concerning the ancient rights of the subject of this realm, chiefly consisting in the privileges of this House of Parliament, the misinformation openly delivered to your Majesty hath been in three things: 
First, That we held not privileges of right, but of grace only, renewed every Parliament by way of donature upon petition, and so to be limited. 
Secondly, That we are no Court of Record, nor yet a Court that can command view of records, but that our proceedings here are only to act and memorials, and that the attendance with the records is courtesy, not duty.
Thirdly and lastly, That the examination of the return of writes for knights and burgesses is without our compass, and due to the Chancery.
 . . .[W]ith all humble and due respect to your Majesty our Sovereign Lord and head, against those misinformations we most truly avouch,
First, That our privileges and liberties are our right and due inheritance, no less than our very lands and goods.
Secondly, That they cannot be withheld from us, denied, or impaired, but with apparent wrong to the whole state of the realm.
Thirdly, And that our making of request in the entrance of Parliament to enjoy our privilege is an act only of manners, and doth weaken our right no more than our suing to the King for our lands by petition….
Fourthly, We avouch also, That our House is a Court of Record, and so ever esteemed.
. . . Sixth and lastly, We avouch that the House of Commons is the sole proper judge of return of all such writs and of the election of all such members as belong to it, without which the freedom of election were not entire….
From these misinformed positions, most gracious Sovereign, the greatest part of our troubles, distrusts, and jealousies have risen….
<font size='8'>From CONSTITUTIONAL DOCUMENTS OF THE REIGN OF JAMES I A.D. 1603-1625 WITH AN HISTORICAL COMMENTARY by J.R. Tanner. Copyright © 1930, 1952 Cambridge University Press.</font>
]]></mainText>
	</slideInfo>	
</TextReading>