<TextReading>
	<slideInfo>
		<hText>Factories, Cities, and Families in the Industrial Age</hText>
		<image></image>
		<audio>audio/euro_m1-4_s20.mp3</audio>
		<mainText><![CDATA[In 1828, a German visitor described Britain as a land where the “new creations springing into life every year bordered on the fabulous.” These creations were the machines and factories of the industrial revolution that were replacing agriculture and handicrafts as the basis of the traditional economy. They turned industrial cities like Manchester into what the French writer Alexis de Tocqueville called “the greatest stream of human industry” that “flows out to fertilize the whole world.” 
However, this wave of industrial developments, which made Britain wealthy and envied, brought disturbing consequences in its wake: great swings of economic prosperity and depression and a new working class harnessed to the rhythm of machines. A British journal in 1826 spoke of a growing ‘accumulation of misery endured by thousands’ in industrial areas. A few years later, the French consul in Edinburgh argued, “Who would want the prosperity of Liverpool and Manchester in France . . . beside these base miseries offered by manufacturing establishments?” 
These “miseries” haunted not only the new factories and mines. Workers hoping for jobs crowded into unprepared cities. There, life for them as well as for middle-class employers, professionals, and shopkeepers was rapidly changing. In bad times, unemployment and business failures made urban life particularly harsh. In prosperous times, filth and disease still marked these cities. Here even the family, which for so long labored together as a cooperating unit of economic life, was shifting under the weight of new ideas and pressures. Western societies were entering the industrial age.

<font size='8'>From THE WEST IN THE WORLD, 4th Edition, by Dennis Sherman and Joyce Salisbury, copyright © 2011 The McGraw-Hill Companies, Inc.</font>]]></mainText>
	</slideInfo>	
</TextReading>

