<TextReading>
	<slideInfo>
		<hText><![CDATA[from <font face='t-Italic'>The Renaissance</font> by Peter Burke<br/><font face='c-Bold'>&quot;The Myth of the Renaissance&quot;</font>]]></hText>
		<image></image>
		<audio>audio/euro_m4-2_s17.mp3</audio>
		<mainText><![CDATA[It was Jacob Burckhardt whose famous <font face='lc-Italic'>Civilisation of the Renaissance in Italy</font> (1860) defined the period in terms of two concepts, ‘individualism’ and ‘modernity’. ‘In the Middle Ages; according to Burckhardt, ‘human consciousness…lay dreaming or half awake beneath a common veil…. Man was conscious of himself only as a member of a race, people, party, family, or corporation—only through some general category.’ In Renaissance Italy, however, 'this veil first melted into air…man became a spiritual individual, and recognized himself as such’. Renaissance meant modernity. The Italian was, Burckhardt wrote, ‘the first-born among the sons of modern Europe’. The fourteenth-century poet Francesco Petrarca (known in English as Petrarch) was ‘one of the first truly modern men’. The great renewal of art and ideas began in Italy, and at a later stage the new attitudes and the new artistic forms spread to the rest of Europe.
     This idea of the Renaissance is a myth...
     Burckhardt’s mistake was to accept the scholars and artists of the period at their own valuation, to take this story of rebirth at its face value and to elaborate it into a book. To the old formulae of the restoration or renewal of the arts and the revival of classical antiquity, he added new ones such as individualism, realism, and modernity….
    This nineteenth-century myth of the Renaissance is still taken seriously by many people. Television companies and organisers of package tours still make money out of it. However, professional historians have become dissatisfied with this version of the Renaissance, even if they continue to admire Michelangelo (say), and to find the period and the movement extremely attractive. The point is that the grand edifice erected by Burckhardt and his contemporaries has not stood the test of time. More exactly, it has been undermined by the researches of the medievalists in particular. Their arguments depend on innumerable points of detail, but they are of two main kinds.
     In the first place, there are arguments to the effect that so-called ‘Renaissance men’ were really rather medieval. They were more traditional in their behaviour, assumptions and ideals than we tend to think—and also more traditional than they saw themselves. Hindsight suggests that even Petrarch, ‘one of the first truly modern men’, according to Burckhardt, ...  shared many attitudes with the centuries he described as ‘dark’...
    In the second place, the medievalists have accumulated arguments to the effect that the Renaissance was not such a singular event as Burckhardt and his contemporaries once thought and that the term should really be used in the plural. There were various ‘renascences’ in the Middle Ages, notably in the twelfth century and in the age of Charlemagne. In both cases there was a combination of literary and artistic achievements with a revival of interest in classical learning, and in both cases contemporaries described their age as one of restoration, rebirth or renewal.<br/><br/><font size='8'>Peter Burke, THE RENAISSANCE, Second Edition, 1997, Macmillan Press Limited. Reproduced with permission of Palgrave Macmillan.</font>]]></mainText>
	</slideInfo>	
</TextReading>