<MultipleChoice>
	<slideInfo>
		<endQuiz>false</endQuiz>
		<audio>audio/euro_m2-5_s12.mp3</audio>
		<endFeedback feedback="" />
		<oneQuestion>true</oneQuestion>
		<Source>
			<Text><![CDATA[<p align="center"><font face='c-Bold'>Document 1: “Microscopy” from </font><font face='c-Bold'><font face='c-Italic'>Experimental Philosophy </font></font><font face='c-Bold'>by Henry Power, 1664</font></p>
<font face='lc-Italic'>Observation XXX</font>
<font face='lc-Italic'>Of the Little White Eels or Snigs, in Vinegar</font>

They appear like small Silver-Eels, or little Snigs, and some of them as long as my little finger, constantly wriggling and swimming to and fro with a quick, smart, and restless motion. In which smallest of Animals these things are most remarkable. 
[T]heir heads and tails are smaller than the rest of their bodies; which is best observed by the microscope, when the liquor wherein they swim is almost spent and dried up, so that their motion thereby is rendered more feeble and weak, or when they lie absolutely dead. 

Now though heat hath that killing property, yet it seems that cold hath not: for I have taken a jar-glass full of the said vinegar, and by applying snow and salt to it, I have artificially frozen all the said liquor into a mass of ice (wherein all those animals it seemed lay incrystalled) though I could discover none of them in it . . . so that now I gave them [up] for gone for ever: yet when I came again (about two or three hours after,) to uncongeal the liquor, by keeping the glass in my warm hand, when the vinegar was again returned to its former liquidity, all my little animals made their reappearance, and danced and frisked about as lively as ever.]]></Text>
			<word>View</word>
			<image></image>
		</Source>
	</slideInfo>
	
	<question>
		<qText>Based on the excerpt from “Microscopy,” which of the following statements is true?</qText>
		<answerButtons>
			<aBtn>
				 <aText>The scientist had no method; he just observed what happened to the animals.</aText> 
			 	<correct>false</correct>
			</aBtn>
			<aBtn>
				 <aText>The scientist was excited by learning about the animals; he had a thirst for knowledge.</aText> 
			 	<correct>true</correct>
			</aBtn>
		</answerButtons>
		<feedback enable="true" audio="audio/euro_m2-5_s12_FB.mp3" />
	</question>

</MultipleChoice>
