<TextReading>
	<slideInfo>
		<hText><![CDATA[Enlightened Despotism: Russia]]></hText>
		<image></image>
		<audio>audio/euro_m4-4_s42.mp3</audio>
		<mainText><![CDATA[<img src="images/euro_m4-4_s42.jpg"/>
		
		
		
		
		
		
		
		
		
		
		
		
		
		
		
		<br/><br/><br/><br/><br/><p>In the Age of Enlightenment the role of Russia was passive. No Russian thinker was known to western Europe, but western European thinkers were well known in Russia. The French-dominated cosmopolitan culture of the European upper classes spread to the upper classes of Russia. The Russian court and aristocracy took over French as their common conversational language. With French all the ideas boiling up in western Europe streamed into Russia. The Enlightenment, if it did not affect Russia profoundly, affected it significantly. It continued the westernization so forcibly pushed forward by Peter and carried further the estrangement of the Russian upper classes from their own people and their own native scene. 
<br/>. . . When [Catherine the Great] first came to power, she publicized an intention to introduce certain enlightened reforms. The reforms which she subsequently enacted consisted in a measure of legal codification [collection and arrangement of laws], restrictions on the use of torture, and a certain support of religious toleration, though she would not allow Old Believers [dissenters who did not accept religious reforms instituted in the 17th century] to build their own chapels. Such innovations were enough to raise an admiring chorus from the philosophes, who saw in her, as they saw retrospectively in Peter the Great, the standard-bearer of an enlightened civilization among a backward people. 
<br/>Whatever ideas Catherine may conceivably have had at first, as a thoughtful and progressive young woman, on the fundamental subject of reforming serfdom in Russia, did not last long after . . . the great peasant insurrection of 1773. . . . The condition of the Russian serfs was deteriorating. Serf owners were increasingly selling them apart from the land, breaking up families, using them in mines or manufactures, disciplining and punishing them at will, or exiling them to Siberia. The serf population was restless, worked upon by Old Believers and cherishing distorted popular memories of [a past revolutionary hero] who had led an uprising against the landlords. Class antagonism, though latent, was profound, nor was it made less when the rough muzhik [Russian peasant], in some places, hear the lord and his family talking French so as not to be understood by the servants or saw them wearing European clothes, reading European books, and adopting the manners of a foreign way of life.</p>
<font size='8'>From A HISTORY OF THE MODERN WORLD, 10th edition, by R.R. Palmer et al., copyright © 2007 The McGraw-Hill Companies, Inc.</font>]]></mainText>
	</slideInfo>	
</TextReading>