<TextReading>
	<slideInfo>
		<hText>Ems Telegram</hText>
		<image></image>
		<audio>audio/euro_m3-1_s24.mp3</audio>
		<mainText><![CDATA[Original Version:
Telegram of Privy Councellor Heinrich Abeken to the Federal Chancellor Count von Bismarck on the 13th of July, 1870, from Ems:
His majesty writes to me [Abeken]: “Count Benedetti [French ambassador to Berlin] spoke to me [the Kaiser] on the promenade, in order to demand from me, finally in a very importunate manner, that I should authorize him to telegraph at once that I bound myself for all future time never again to give my consent if the Hohenzollerns [the Kaiser’s family] should renew their candidature [for the throne of Spain]. I refused at last somewhat sternly, as it is neither right nor possible to undertake engagements of this kind <font face='c-Italic'>á tout jamais</font> [forever]. Naturally I told him that I had as yet received no news, and as he was earlier informed about Paris and Madrid than myself, he could clearly see that my government once more had no hand in the matter.” His majesty has since received a letter from the Prince [learning that the Hohenzollern prince had turned down the offer from Spain]. His Majesty having told Count Benedetti that he was awaiting news from the Prince, has decided, with a reference to the above demand, upon the presentation of Count Eulenburg [a Prussian government minister] and myself, not to receive Count Benedetti again, but only to let him be informed through an aide-de-camp: That his Majesty had now received from the Prince confirmation of the news which Benedetti had already received from Paris, and had nothing further to say to the ambassador. His Majesty leaves it to your Excellency [Bismarck] whether Benedetti’s fresh demand and its rejection should not be a once communicated both to our ambassadors and to the press.

Version edited by Bismarck:
After the news of the renunciation of the hereditary Prince of Hohenzollern had been officially communicated to the imperial government of France by the royal government of Spain, the French ambassador at Ems further demanded of his Majesty the King that he would authorize him to telegraph to Paris that his Majesty the King bound himself for all future time never again to give his consent if the Hohenzollerns should renew their candidature. His Majesty the King thereupon decided not to receive the French ambassador again, and sent to tell him through the aide-de-camp on duty that his Majesty had nothing further to communicate to the ambassador. 

]]></mainText>
	</slideInfo>	
</TextReading>

