<TextReading>
	<slideInfo>
		<hText>Europe Transformed: Explaining the New Imperialism</hText>
		<image></image>
		<audio>audio/euro_m4-3_s20.mp3</audio>
		<mainText><![CDATA[<p>No single factor can explain the new imperialism. Rather, it emerged out of a number of significant changes that occurred in Europe during the second half of the nineteenth century.
By the late nineteenth century, Europeans had access to new and astonishingly efficient technologies that would change the course of colonial conquest and domination. To be sure, technology had played a major role in spreading European influence abroad throughout the nineteenth century and earlier; steamships, industrial weaponry, and the use of quinine to treat malaria had allowed Europeans to penetrate continental Africa, and the arrival of gunboats—armed steamboats—had played decisive roles, for example in the conquest of Burma and the opening of China. Nevertheless, the advent of the second industrial revolution in the late nineteenth century made technology an even more important factor in the speed, extent, and vigor of the conquests. Ironclad warships with steam turbines now spread the power of far more advanced and deadly European weaponry overseas, while the invention of the telegraph radically simplified the logistics of military mobilization from afar.
… Most historians would agree that it was nationalism—understood in the broadest sense of the term—that propelled the new imperialism forward. Although nationalism was hardly new, it developed in strikingly new ways during this period… Based on emotional appeals to community and history, the new nationalism challenged the liberal politics of the midcentury based on the rational individual and the possibilities of societal progress. Imperial domination, in this context was seen as a sign of national vigor and a marker of prestige.
…Within this charged nationalist framework, economic, political, and cultural forces each played their role in promoting the imperial scramble. Economic factors were critical. As they had done earlier in the century, turn-of-the-century imperial nations viewed their colonies as vital markets for selling European industrial goods, buying raw materials and cash crops, and investing surplus capital. But now the economic context had changed. One new factor was the presence of Germany [recently unified in 1871] and the United States as leading industrial powers. By 1890 both Germany and the United States had surpassed British steel and iron production and Germany was outselling the British in certain overseas markets… Finally, the advent of a new, more advanced phase of industrial capitalism in the late nineteenth century brought with it fears of saturation of the domestic market and, with that, industrial overproduction. In this context, many Europeans came to view empire as an essential outlet for surpluses of goods and capital…
The primacy of the nation-state during this period also put strategic and territorial ambitions at center stage. The actions of European nations within the imperial arena were taken as much to jockey for political power and to preempt the territorial claims of other nations as they were to pursue economic gain. 
In the cultural realm, too, late-nineteenth-century nation-states mobilized imperialism to assist with internal processes of state-building. Newly unified nation-states [such as German and Italy], in particular, but older and established ones as well, actively sought to fully unify their citizens, in large part by inducing them to transfer their primary loyalties from their local community to the far more abstract, “imagined” community of the nation. This process met with significant resistance, particularly since it entailed a loss of regional identity, and national leaders used the attractions of empire as one means of appealing to its citizens. Empire was presented as the shared symbolic property of the nation, an asset that in theory (but not in practice) transcended social class and allowed peasants and workers—as much as members of the upper classes—to cast themselves as superior to the nation’s virile masculinity, seen in favorable contrast to the supposedly weak, "effeminate" colony. Imperialism and, more specifically, imperial racism helped to consolidate the nation-state, in other words, by substituting race hierarchies for the hierarchies of class.
<font size='8'>From THE WESTERN EXPERIENCE, 10th Edition, by Mortimer Chambers et al, copyright © 2010 The McGraw-Hill Companies, Inc. p. 745-747</font></p>]]></mainText>
	</slideInfo>	
</TextReading>