<TextReading>
	<slideInfo>
		<hText>The Agricultural Revolution in Britain</hText>
		<image></image>
		<audio>audio/euro_m1-4_s19.mp3</audio>
		<mainText><![CDATA[The English Revolution of 1688, confirming the ascendency of Parliament over the king, meant in economic terms the ascendency of the more well-to-do property-owning classes.  . . . For a century and a half, from 1688 to 1832, the British government was substantially in the hands of these landowners—the “squirearchy” or “gentlemen of England.” The result was a thorough transformation of farming, an Agricultural Revolution without which the Industrial Revolution could not have occurred. 
Many landowners, seeking to increase their money incomes, began experimenting with improved methods of cultivation and [live]stock raising. 
. . . An improving landlord, to introduce such changes successfully, needed full control over his land. He saw only a barrier to progress in the old village system of open fields, common lands, and semicollective methods of cultivation. Improvement also required an investment of capital, which was impossible so long as the soil was tilled by numerous poor and custom-bound small farmers. The old common rights of villagers were part of the English common law. Only an act of Parliament could modify or extinguish them. It was the great landowners who controlled Parliament, which therefore passed hundreds of “enclosure acts,” authorizing the enclosure, by fences, walls, or hedges, of the old common lands and unfenced open fields. Land thus came under a strict regime of private ownership and individual management. 
. . . One result was greatly to raise the productivity of land and of farm labor.  . . . Labor was thus released for other pursuits. The greater number of English country people became wage earners, working for farmers and landlords, or spinning or weaving in their cottages for merchants in the towns. English working men and women were therefore dependent on daily wages long before the coming of the factory and the machine. Working people became mobile; they would go where jobs were, or where the wages were slightly higher. They also became available for new kinds of work because fewer of them were needed on land to produce food. 

<font size='8'>From A HISTORY OF THE MODERN WORLD, 10th edition, by R.R. Palmer et al., copyright © 2007 The McGraw-Hill Companies, Inc.</font>]]></mainText>
	</slideInfo>	
</TextReading>

