<TextReading>
	<slideInfo>
		<hText><![CDATA[<font face='t-Italic' >Of The Social Contract </font>by Jean-Jacques Rousseau]]></hText>
		<image></image>
		<audio>audio/euro_m3-3_s17.mp3</audio>
		<mainText><![CDATA[To find a form of association that will defend and protect the person and goods of each associate with the full common force, and by means of which each, uniting with all, nevertheless obey only himself and remain as free as before. This is the fundamental problem to which the social contract provides the solution. 
If, then, one sets aside everything that is not of the essence of the social compact, one finds that it can be reduced to the following terms: <font face='lc-Italic' >Each of us puts his person and his full power in common under the supreme direction of the general will; and in a body we receive each member as an indivisible part of the whole.</font>
At once, in place of the private person of each contracting party, this act of association produces a moral and collective body made up of as many members as the assembly has voices, and which receives by this same act its unity, its common self, its life and its will. The public person thus formed by the union of all the others formerly assumed the name <font face='lc-Italic' >City</font> and now assumes that of <font face='lc-Italic' >Republic</font> or of <font face='lc-Italic' >body politic</font>, which its members call <font face='lc-Italic' >State</font> when it is passive, <font face='lc-Italic' >Sovereign</font> when active, <font face='lc-Italic' >Power</font> when comparing it to similar bodies. As for the associates, they collectively assume the name <font face='lc-Italic' >people</font> and individually call themselves <font face='lc-Italic' >Citizens</font> as participants in the sovereign authority, and <font face='lc-Italic' >Subjects</font> as subjected to the laws of the state.
<br/><font size='8'>From THE SOCIAL CONTRACT AND OTHER LATER POLITICAL WRITINGS by Jean-Jacques Rousseau, edited and translated by Victor Gourevitch. Copyright © 1997 Cambridge University Press.</font>]]></mainText>
	</slideInfo>	
</TextReading>