<TextReading>
	<slideInfo>
		<hText><![CDATA[ from <font face='t-Italic'>Politics Drawn from the Very Words of Holy Scripture</font> by Jacques-Benigne Bossuet, 1709]]></hText>
		<image></image>
		<audio>audio/euro_m3-3_s5.mp3</audio>
		<mainText><![CDATA[<p>God, moreover, has put something divine into kings. “I have said: You are Gods, and all of you the sons of the most High.” It is God himself whom David makes speak this way. 
. . . Their power coming from on high, as has been said, they must not believe that they are the owners of it, to use it as they please; rather must they use it with fear and restraint, as something which comes to them from God, and for which God will ask an accounting of them.
. . . Kings must tremble, then, in using the power that God gives them, and consider how horrible is the sacrilege of using for evil a power that comes from God.<br/>
<font face='lc-Bold'>Royal authority is absolute</font><br/>In order to make this term [absolute] odious and insupportable, many [writers] pretend to confuse absolute government with arbitrary government. But nothing is more distinct, as we shall make clear when we speak of justice. 
1st Proposition: <font face='lc-Italic'>The prince need account to no one for what he ordains</font><br/>“Observe the mouth of the king, and the commandments of the oath of God. Be not hasty to depart from his face, and do not continue in an evil work: for he will do all that pleaseth him. And his word is full of power: neither can any man say to him: Why dost thou so? He that keepeth the commandment shall find no evil.” [from Ecclesiastes Chapter 8, Verses 2-5]
<br/>Without this absolute authority, he can neither do good nor suppress evil: his power must be such that no one can hope to escape him; and, in fine, the sole defense of individuals saying against the public power, must be their innocence.<br/>This doctrine is in conformity with the saying of St. Paul: “Wilt thou then not be afraid of the power? Do that which is good.” 
2st Proposition: <font face='lc-Italic'>When the prince has decided, there can be no other decision</font><br/>The judgments of sovereigns are attributed to God himself. 
. . . One must, then, obey princes as if they were justice itself, without which there is neither order nor justice in affairs. They are Gods . . . only God can judge their judgments and their persons.
. . . He who creates a sovereign prince puts everything together into his hands, both the sovereign authority to judge and all the power of the state.
<br/><font size='8'>From POLITICS DRAWN FROM THE VERY WORDS OF HOLY SCRIPTURE, translated and edited by Patrick Riley. Copyright © 1990 Cambridge University Press.</font>

<p>]]></mainText>
	</slideInfo>	
</TextReading>