<TextReading>
	<slideInfo>
		<hText><![CDATA[Martin Luther]]></hText>
		<image></image>
		<audio>audio/euro_m4-2_s21.mp3</audio>
		<mainText><![CDATA[<p>The two fundamental assertions of [Martin] Luther’s teachings derive from the emphasis on God’s power and mystery that Luther learned in his nominalist monastery. First, faith alone—not good works or the receiving of the sacraments—justifies the believer in the eyes of God and wins redemption. People themselves are helpless and unworthy sinners who can do nothing to cooperate in their own salvation; God bestows faith on those he chooses to save. Second, the Bible is the sole source of religious authority. It alone carries the word of God, and Christians must reject all other authorities: Church tradition, commentaries on the Bible, or the pronouncements of popes and Church councils.
   These two doctrines had far-reaching implications. According to Luther, all people are equally capable of understanding God’s word as expressed in the Bible and can gain salvation without the help of intermediaries; they do not need a priest endowed with special powers or an interceding church. Luther thus saw God’s faithful as a “priesthood of all believers,” a concept totally foreign to the traditional [Catholic] Church, which insisted on the distinction between clergy and laity. The distinction disappeared in Luther’s doctrines, because all the faithful shared the responsibilities formerly reserved for priests.
   True to his reliance on biblical authority, Luther retained only two sacraments—baptism and the Eucharist—as a means by which God distributes grace. Moreover, the ceremony of the Eucharist was now called communion (literally, “sharing”) to emphasize that all worshipers, including the officiating clergy, were equal; all shared both wafer and wine. Luther also reduced the distinctiveness of priests by giving them the right to marry.
   Luther’s teachings on the sacraments transformed the Mass, the ceremony that surrounds the Eucharist. According to traditional dogma, when the priest raises the wafer, the host, during the Mass and recites the words Hoc est corpus meum (“This is my body”), the sacrifice of Jesus on the cross is reenacted. The wafer and the wine retain their outward appearance, their “accidents,” but their substance is transformed into the body and blood of Christ—in other words, transubstantiation takes place.
   Luther asserted that the wafer and wine retain their substance as well as their accidents at the moment the priest says, “This is my body.” The real presence of Christ and the natural substance coexist within the wafer and wine. Nothing suddenly happens; there is no miraculous moment. Instead, the believer is simply made aware of the real presence of God, who is everywhere at all times… Moreover, by allowing the congregation to drink the wine…Luther further reduced the mystery of the Lord’s Supper and undermined the position of the priest. And by abolishing the use of Latin, processions, incense, and votive candles he simplified services and gave ordinary people a greater role in worship.
   With the priest reduced in stature, it was vital to make God’s word more readily available to the faithful, so that they could read or hear the Bible for themselves. To this end, Luther began the long task of translating the Bible [into German]. Families were encouraged to read Scripture on their own, and the reformed faith stimulated rising literacy among women as well as men…
   The advance of Lutheranism…had depended largely on its appeal to the ordinary believer, and it continued to enjoy widespread support. But when Luther was forced to choose between the demands of his humblest followers and the authority of the princes who had protected him, he opted for the princes. It was a decision that enabled his movement to survive and may well have saved him [from execution].  Had Luther not condemned the [peasant revolts], he would doubtless have been abandoned by the princes, and without their backing he and his followers could not have stood up to the [Catholic] Church or been safe from the power of [Holy Roman Emperor] Charles V. 
   <font size='8'>From THE WESTERN EXPERIENCE, 10th edition, by Mortimer Chambers et al., copyright © 2010 The McGraw-Hill Companies, Inc.</font></p>]]></mainText>
	</slideInfo>	
</TextReading>