<TextReading>
	<slideInfo>
		<hText><![CDATA[Russia After 1881: Reaction and Progress]]></hText>
		<image></image>
		<audio>audio/euro_m4-4_s45.mp3</audio>
		<mainText><![CDATA[Although still industrially undeveloped by Western standards, Russia was industrializing rapidly. Exports rose in value from 400 million rubles in 1880 to 1.6 billion in 1913. Imports, though smaller, grew more rapidly, quintupling in the same period. They consisted of such items as tea and coffee and the machines and industrial goods made in western Europe. 
Industrialization, in Russia, as in all countries, brought an increase both of the business and of the wage-earning classes, or, in socialist terminology, of the bourgeoisie and of the proletariat. Though growing, they were still not numerous by the standards of the West. Factory workers, laboring for 11 or more hours a day for low wages under hard conditions, were in somewhat the same position as in England or France before 1850. Unions were illegal and strikes were prohibited. 
. . . The rising business and professional classes, reinforced by enterprising landowners, were strong enough to form a liberal segment of public opinion, which emerged in 1905 as the Constitutional Democratic party.  …They were liberals, progressives, or constitutionalists in the Western sense, thinking less about the troubles of factory workers and peasants than about the need for a nationally elected parliament to control the policies of state. 
Russia remained predominately agricultural. Its huge exports were mainly farm and forest products. The peasants formed four-fifths of the population. Free from their former lords since 1861 [when serfs were emancipated or freed], they lived in village communes called mirs. In most communes much of the land was divided and redivided among peasant households by agreement of the village community, nor could anyone leave without communal permission. These peasants still carried a considerable burden. 
<font size='8'>From A HISTORY OF THE MODERN WORLD, 10th edition, by R.R. Palmer et al., copyright © 2007 The McGraw-Hill Companies, Inc.</font>]]></mainText>
	</slideInfo>	
</TextReading>