<TextReading>
	<slideInfo>
		<hText>The Prussian Military State</hText>
		<image></image>
		<audio>audio/euro_m2-4_s8.mp3</audio>
		<mainText><![CDATA[The preoccupation of Prussia with its army was unquestionably defensive in origin, arising from the horrors of the Thirty Years’ War. But it outlasted its cause and became the settled habit and character of the country. Prussia was not unique in the attention it paid to its armed forces. The unique thing about Prussia was the disproportion between the size of the army and the size of the resources on which the army was based. The government, to maintain the army, had to direct and plan the life of the country for this purpose. 
. . . But Prussia was unique in that, more than any other country, the army developed a life of its own, almost independent of the life of the state. It was older than the Prussian state. In 1657 the Great Elector [Frederick William, Elector of Brandenburg and Duke of Prussia] fought a great battle at Warsaw with soldiers from all parts of his dominions. It was the first time that men from Cleves, Brandenburg, and ducal Prussia had ever done anything together. The army was the first “all Prussian” institution. Institutions of civilian government developed later and largely to meet the needs of the army. And in later generations the army proved more durable than the state. When Prussia collapsed before Napoleon in 1806, the spirit and morale of the Prussian army carried on; and when the Hohenzollern empire finally crashed in 1918, the army still maintained its life and traditions on into the Weimar Republic, which again it survived. Not until the defeat of Adolf Hitler in the Second World War and the establishment of a new republican regime was the army totally subordinated to civilian authority. <br /><br /><font size = "14">From A HISTORY OF THE MODERN WORLD, 10th edition, by R.R. Palmer et al., copyright © 2007 The McGraw-Hill Companies, Inc.</font>]]></mainText>
	</slideInfo>	
</TextReading>