<TextReading>
	<slideInfo>
		<hText>The Printing Press</hText>
		<image></image>
		<audio>audio/euro_m4-1_s7.mp3</audio>
		<mainText><![CDATA[<p>By the middle of the fifteenth century several masters were on the verge of perfecting the technique of printing with movable metal type. The first to prove this practicable was Johannes Guttenberg of Mainz, a former jeweler and stonecutter… His Bible, printed in 1455, is the first major work reproduced through printing. The technique spread rapidly. By 1500 some 250 cities had presses…<br/>The immediate effect of the printing press was to multiply the output and cut the cost of books. It made information available to a much broader segment of the population, and libraries could store more information at lower cost. Printing helped disseminate and preserve knowledge in standardized form—a major contribution to the advance of technology and scholarship. Printing produced a revolution in what we would call information technology, and indeed it resembles in many ways the profound changes that computers are making in our own lives. Finally, printing could spread new ideas with unprecedented speed…<br/>By the mid-1400s [Renaissance] Humanism dominated intellectual life in much of Italy, and by 1500 it was sweeping all of Europe, transmitted by its devotees and also … printing, which made the texts of both humanist and ancients far more easily available. Dozens of new schools and universities were founded, and no court of any significance was without its roster of artists and writers familiar with the latest ideas. Even legal systems were affected, as the principles of Roman law were adopted in many countries…<br/>Printers quickly took advantage of the popular interest in books by publishing almanacs filled with home-spun advice about the weather and nature that were written specifically for simple rural folk. Even the almanacs, however, carried religious advice. More importantly, translations of the Bible made it available to ordinary people in language that, for the first time, they could understand. Books thus became powerful weapons in the religious conflicts of the day. Devotional tracts, lives of the saints, and the Bible were the most popular titles--often running to editions of around one thousand copies. They became the means of spreading new ideas, and the ready markets they found reflected the general interest of the age in spiritual matters.<br/>Printing lessened the dependence of ordinary people on the clergy; whereas traditionally the priest had read and interpreted the Scriptures for his congregation, now people could consult their own copies. By 1522, eighteen translations of the Bible had been published. Some fourteen thousand copies had been printed in German alone, enough to make it easy to buy in most German-speaking regions. The Church frowned on these efforts, and governments tried to regulate the numbers and locations of presses; but in the end it proved impossible to control the effects of printing.<br/><br/><font size='8'>From THE WESTERN EXPERIENCE, 10th edition, by Mortimer Chambers et al., copyright © 2010 The McGraw-Hill Companies, Inc.</font></p>]]></mainText>
	</slideInfo>	
</TextReading>