<TextReading>
	<slideInfo>
		<hText><![CDATA[Leviathan: Political Order and Political Theory]]></hText>
		<image></image>
		<audio>audio/euro_m4-4_s21.mp3</audio>
		<mainText><![CDATA[                                                             <font face='c-Italic' size='20'>Thomas Hobbes</font><br/><br/>Background: <font face='lc-Italic'>Although England avoided the Thirty Years’ War [1618-1648] she had her own experiences with passionate war and disruption of authority. Between 1640 and 1660 England endured the civil war, the trial and execution of her king, Charles I, the rise to power of Oliver Cromwell, and the return to power of the Stuart king, Charles II. These events stimulated Thomas Hobbes (1588-1679) to formulate one of the most important statements of political theory in history.</font>
The only way to erect such a common power, as may be able to defend [the people] from the invasion of foreigners, and the injuries of one another, and thereby to secure them in such sort, as that by their own industry, and by the fruits of the earth, they may nourish themselves and live contentedly; is, to confer all their power and strength upon one man, or upon one assembly of men, that may reduce all their wills, by plurality of voices, unto one will: which is as much as to say, to appoint one man, or assembly of men, to bear their person; and every one to own, and acknowledge himself to be author of whatsoever he that so beareth their person, shall act, or cause to be acted, in those things which concern the common peace and safety; and therein to submit their will, every one to his will, and their judgments, to his judgment. This is more than consent, or concord; it is a real unity of them all, in one and the same person, made by covenant of every man with every man, in such manner, as if every man should say to every man, I authorize and give up my right of governing myself, to this man, or to this assembly of men, on this condition, that thou give up thy right to him, and authorize all his actions in like manner. This done, the multitude so united in one person, is called a COMMONWEALTH,….For by this authority, given him by every particular man in the commonwealth, he hath the use of so much power and strength conferred on him, that by terror thereof, he is enabled to perform the wills of them all, to peace at home, and mutual aid against their enemies abroad. And in him consisteth the essence of the commonwealth; which to define it, is one person, of whose acts a great multitude, by mutual covenants one with another, have made themselves every one the author, to the end he may use the strength and means of them all, as he shall think expedient, for their peace and common defence.
And he that carrieth this person, is called SOVEREIGN, and said to have  <font face='lc-Italic'>sovereign power;</font> and every one besides, his SUBJECT.
]]></mainText>
	</slideInfo>	
</TextReading>