<TextReading>
	<slideInfo>
		<hText></hText>
		<image></image>
		<audio>audio/eng_m3-3_s14.mp3</audio>
		<mainText><![CDATA[     Gregory Powell spaced his words for emphasis, "One week ago, Donovan and I put you together." His brows furrowed doubtfully and he pulled the end of his brown mustache.<br/>      It was quiet in the officer's room of Solar Station #5—except for the soft purring of the mighty Beam Director somewhere far below.<br/>     Robot QT-1 sat immovable. The burnished plates of his body gleamed in the Luxites and the glowing red of the photoelectric cells that were his eyes, were fixed steadily upon the Earthman at the other side of the table.<br/>     Powell repressed a sudden attack of nerves. These robots possessed peculiar brains. Oh, the three Laws of Robotics held. They had to. All of U. S. Robots, from Robertson himself to the new floor-sweeper would insist on that. So QT-1 was <font face='lc-Italic'>safe!</font> And yet—the QT models were the first of their kind, and this was the first of the QTs. Mathematical squiggles on paper were not always the most comforting protection against robotic fact.<br/>     Finally, the robot spoke. His voice carried the cold timbre inseparable from a metallic diaphragm, "Do you realize the seriousness of such a statement, Powell?"<br/>     "<font face="lc-Italic">Something</font> made you, Cutie," pointed out Powell. "You admit yourself that your memory seems to spring full-grown from an absolute blankness of a week ago. I'm giving you the explanation. Donovan and I put you together from the parts shipped us."<br/>     Cutie gazed upon his long, supple fingers in an oddly human attitude of mystification, "It strikes me that there should be a more satisfactory explanation than that. For <font face="lc-Italic">you</font> to make <font face="lc-Italic">me</font> seems improbable."
<br/><br/><font size="14">"Reason," from I, ROBOT by Isaac Asimov, copyright 1950 by Isaac Asimov. Used by permission of Bantam Books, a division of Random House, Inc.</font>]]></mainText>
	</slideInfo>	
</TextReading>