<TextReading>
	<slideInfo>
		<hText>INTRODUCTION</hText>
		<image></image>
		<audio>audio/eng_m3-5_s12.mp3</audio>
		<mainText><![CDATA[<p>          People have made amazing technological progress within the last century. Decades before man landed on the moon and long before the establishment of the International Space Station, in an era when one of the most advanced technological achievements was the use of an airplane for aerial bombardment, Isaac Asimov was writing about space stations and humanlike robots. Asimov was not only an author and biochemist but also a futurist, predicting some amazing achievements such as housing men in outer space. Although filled with the promise of great accomplishments, Asimov poses some questions about man and the relationship with the machines he builds. The title of his book of short stories—<font face='lc-Italic'>I, Robot</font> —hints at the idea of a machine with a mind of its own. By creating an EERIE SITUATION, making the PROTAGONIST DOUBTFUL, and ending the passage with an IRONIC STATEMENT, Asimov reveals his skeptical attitude toward technology in his short story “Reason.”<br/><br/><font face='lc-Bold'>BODY</font><br/>          Several details from the passage depict an eerie, uncomfortable scene. Gregory Powell and his coworker Donovan appear to be isolated, surrounded only by machines, in a space station. The setting is “quiet” with the only sounds initially coming from the “Beam Director,” an entity that must also be a machine because it is “purring . . . somewhere far below.” Powell is alone in the “officer’s room,” having a disturbing conversation with a robot. Even the description of the robot is troubling. First, it has “glowing red” eyes reminiscent of the demonic eyes in classic horror stories. Second, its “cold timbre” voice has an unnatural, disconcerting sound. Also upsetting is the robot’s behavior because it has an “oddly human attitude.” By using all of these unsettling features in his scene, Asimov cautions the reader about relying too much on technology.<br/><br/>         Asimov’s cautionary tone is also evident in his protagonist’s attitude towards the robot. From the beginning of the passage, Gregory Powell is unsure about the robot. This is evident when “his brows furrowed doubtfully,” and when the robot stares at him, Powell holds back “a sudden attack of nerves.” Then beginning in the fourth paragraph, Powell has an internal monologue trying to convince himself that the robot is <font face='lc-Italic'>“safe!”</font> By placing this word in italics, Asimov reveals that Powell is not really sure of the robot. This doubt is also evident in Asimov’s syntax in the monologue using fragments and dashes to show Powell’s anxiety. Furthermore, contrasting “Mathematical squiggles . . . against robot fact” exposes Powell’s, as well as Asimov’s, lack of certainty concerning this modern technology.<br/><br/>          Asimov’s use of irony throughout the passage further illustrates his skeptical attitude in relation to developing robots. By juxtaposing a logical, emotional machine to an unsure, doubtful scientist, Asimov shows the irony that the robot is in control of the situation. The fact that the machine questions its creator is unexpected. In addition, irony is evident when the robot chastises the man for the “seriousness of such a statement” in a role reversal of a parental figure. Moreover, man did not plan for the “robotic fact” that the machine could think for itself. Finally, for the machine to say “For <font face='lc-Italic'>you</font> to make <font face='lc-Italic'>me</font> seems improbable,” to his creator is unquestionably ironic because we do not expect a machine, even one with artificial intelligence, to be condescending toward a human. The irony in the passage is Asimov’s way of stating that man should maintain a healthy dose of skepticism before embracing machines that can argue and reason.<br/><br/><font face='lc-Bold'>CONCLUSION</font> 
To be continued. . . .		
</p>]]></mainText>
	</slideInfo>	
</TextReading> 