<TextReading>
	<slideInfo>
		<hText></hText>
		<image></image>
		<audio>audio/eng_m3-6_s43.mp3</audio>
		<mainText><![CDATA[<font face='c-Bold'>Body Draft</font><br/>	First, the writer sets the stage for the performance. He must understand the controversial topic and be enthusiastic about discussing his viewpoints just as a dancer must know and be eager to use a musical selection. In preparation, both the writer and the dancer must consider who is in the audience and how the audience feels about the selected topic. The writer needs to identify the situation or issue and present the controversial points clearly. Then, if the writer has any technical or special vocabulary pertaining to the topic, he needs to define these key terms. The dancer, in similar fashion, identifies major points and defines special vocabulary in the Playbill, or the performance booklet that the audience receives upon entering the theater. Also, both the writer and the dancer must establish parameters, the boundaries or limitations of their delivery. Finally, they need to take the lead and clearly establish their position to let the audience know where they stand on the stage for this topic or selection.<br/>	After they have set the stage, the writer and the dancer are ready to start the show by taking a position and engaging the audience. An important factor with any performance is to know the audience and to understand how best to interact with it. According to the Greek philosopher Aristotle, a person can apply three types of appeal to connect to the public. The first, ethos, is an ethical appeal that helps the writer or the dancer to establish his credibility, either through his own credentials or through those that he uses to accompany him. In the dancer’s case, his accompaniment consists of the experts he uses for choreography, musical interpretations, and/or co-performers. In the writer’s case, he is accompanied by the sources he cites. No true performer faces the audience in isolation. <br/>	A second type of appeal, logos, is the logical appeal in which the writer states his evidence by citing facts, presenting statistics, or using logic and reason. This logical appeal may seem unnecessary for a dancer, but the dancer also must maintain a logical sense of rhythm and patterns. One must remember that music is a mathematical and therefore logical equation. Depending on the topic or selection, the writer and dancer want to choose carefully how to use these appeals in engaging their audience.<br/>	Pathos, the third way to engage the public, is an appeal to the emotions of the audience. The writer presents specific anecdotes and evidence to produce a desired feeling and reaction toward his position on the topic. Likewise, the dancer evokes a specific emotion through his facial expressions and body movements.<br/>	For the body paragraphs or the main section of the performance, the writer needs to gather and evaluate evidence. In the dance metaphor, this is the time to choose the choreography. In any routine or presentation, the dancer can Cha-Cha-Cha as well as Two-Step for a more interesting, fresh performance. Like the dancer, the writer must carefully choose his choreography by skillfully gathering and evaluating his evidence. Therefore, the writer must consider the steps that he will take in pulling evidence to give support to his main point or assertion. First, he can <font face='lc-Italic'>Hip-Hop</font> with current events, or check the news for any event that could support his assertion. Second, in searching for evidence, he can <font face='lc-Italic'>Fox Trot</font> with history, or use his interdisciplinary connection and recall what he learned in social studies classes. A third way to find evidence is to make a connection to something in literature and <font face='lc-Italic'>Waltz</font> with a literary theme. Finally, he can count on his own experience for evidence to support his assertion, and <font face='lc-Italic'>Swing</font> with a personal anecdote.<br/>	In evaluating evidence, the writer, like the dancer, must assess the effectiveness of his routine. First, the information must be relevant to his main point. Second, the evidence must represent a variety of sources rather than just one or two. Third, the evidence should be sufficient to leave the audience satisfied. Furthermore, he should be careful not to take any missteps, such as presenting vague or false information. These missteps or logical fallacies would make him lose credibility with his public. <br/>	Just as a dancer would bow to acknowledge his competitor, the writer should give credit to the best points of the opposing argument. That is, he should concede valid points on the other side. However, he should also be prepared to surpass those points with his rebuttal. This is similar to the dancer’s attitude saying, “You’re good, but watch me outperform you.” Snap!<br/>	Lastly is the grand finale. Comparatively, the writer and the dancer will remind the audience of how important this performance has been. They will leave their public applauding for an encore. And long after they have left the stage, the audience will recall and be influenced by the echo of the dance steps.]]></mainText>
	</slideInfo>	
</TextReading>